遗忘天下，个人翻译，如有错误，万望海涵
译制：遗忘天下 后期校订：遗忘天下 上传：遗忘天下
QQ号：529098103 欢迎车迷同学加好友
Top Gear-完美公路之旅
克拉克森：这是英国一个寻常的周二
CLARKSON:It's a normal Tuesday in Britain.
天空伴随着些许小雨，交通已近乎瘫痪
There's a hint of drizzle in the air and traffic is at a standstill.
我们知道驾驶的意义远不像我们看到的这般无趣
We know that driving is meant to be more fun than this.
我们也同样希望汽车应该做些比这更有乐趣的事情
We know that cars are meant to be more fun than this.
因此我们决定做点什么能让您暂时摆脱这混乱的现实世界
So we decided what we'd do is give you an hour or so of escapism,
以给予您一个小时的完美公路驾驶之旅
of perfect roads and perfect cars.
没错。所以我们将要做的是
Yeah. So, what we're going to do is
抛开所有这些让人抓狂的交通状况
strip away all the things that drive us mad,
道路施工，标致汽车，限速摄像头...
roadworks, Peugeots, speed cameras...
-詹姆士·梅。-没错，我们要远离他
-James May. -Yeah, we'll get rid of him.
他总是拖我们的后腿
He's always holding us up.
最后我们会以一次完美的公路之旅结束本次节目
And then we will end up with the perfect road trip.
哈蒙德：意外的是杰瑞米坚持认为本次旅程的起点应该选在这里，威尼斯
Hammond：strangely，Jeremy insisted we should start here，in Venice
一个以水代路的地方
where all the streets are fuLL of wster.
为啥我们要来威尼斯？
Why are we in Venice?
因为我想驾驶丽娃aquariva
(意大利顶级游艇品牌丽娃推出的高速游艇aquariva，)。
Because I wanted to drive the Riva Aquariva。
为什么？
Why?
因为它是有史以来人类制造的最精美交通工具
Because it's the most beautiful thing ever made
并且它还配备了两台V8引擎
and because it's got two V8s.
好吧，我们从威尼斯开始本次旅程因为他想驾驶...这玩意叫啥来着？
Okay, we are starting in Venice because he wanted to drive a... What is it?
-丽娃Aquariva。-丽娃Aquariva。
-Riva Aquariva.-Riva Aquariva.
-有史以来最漂亮的交通工具。-有史以来最漂亮的交通工具。
-The most beautiful thing ever made.-The most beautiful thing ever made
并且还搭载了...两台V8引擎？
and it's got... Two V8s?
-两台V8.-两台V8！
-Two V8s.-Two V8s!
并且我们将从这里出发，开启一段横跨意大利，
And we're going to set off from here on a journey across Italy,
横跨法国的旅程，去到...我们要去哪？
across France, to... Where are we going?
-波城。-去波城...波城？（波城，法国西南部城市，避寒胜地）
-Pau. -To Pau... Pau?
为啥我们要去波城？
Why are we going to Pau?
因为那里是第一届欧洲汽车大奖赛举办的地方
Because that is where the first ever Grand Prix was held.
-波城？-没错。
-Pau? -Yeah.
-从未听说。-老赛道还保留在那。
-Never heard of it.-The track's still there.
我们将去第一届欧洲大奖赛的举办地体验驾驶乐趣
We're going to drive the very first Grand Prix track.
不管怎样。从这里到波城，我们会经历高速公路，
Whatever. Between here and there,we're going to be on motorways,
盘山公路，拉力赛道，专业赛车场，以及城市道路的挑战
mountain roads, rally stages,racetracks and cities.
并且在每一处地点，我们都会选择
And in every place, we are both going to pick what we believe
我们认为最完美的交通方式
is the perfect mode of transport.
我们会度过一周完美的旅程
It's going to be the perfect week.
完美的天气，完美的起点，完美的游艇，完美的一切！
Perfect weather, perfect start,perfect boat, perfect everything!
-完美。-并且没有詹姆士·梅的存在
-Perfect.-And no James May.
这点比完美更重要
That's better than perfect.
克拉克森：在接下来追寻完美的七天旅程中，
CLARKSON: Over the next seven dsys,our quest for perfection
我们会从威尼斯前往意大利湖
wouLd tske us from Venice towsrds the italian lakes.
再从那里沿着法国的蔚蓝海岸线
From there we'd head south to the Mediterranean,
直奔地中海度假胜地圣特罗佩
（圣特罗佩：毗邻嘎纳、摩纳哥，法国著名度假海港小镇）
for a drive aLong the French Riviera to Saint-Tropez.
最后我们回转至内陆去往本次旅程的终点波城
Then we'd swing inland again towsrds the finishing point st Psu.
我们看起来像不像塔布斯和克罗克特？
（美国电视犯罪系列剧迈阿密风云里的人物）
Do we look like Tubbs and Crockett?
或者一对傻胖子和小搞怪？
Or Tubby and Crotchety?
-别，认真点。真的很完美。-傻胖子和小搞怪。
-No, seriously. That's perfect, though. -Tubby and Crotchety.
威尼斯风云（调侃迈阿密风云-Miami Vice）
Venice Vice.
克拉克森：把价值20万欧元的游艇泊好后
CLARKSON: Having docked the £200,000 speedbost,
我为自己挑选了一辆更昂贵的座驾
I switched to an even more expensive car.
更加成熟、车尾一点也不躁动的新款奔驰SLS黑色运动版跑车
The new, grown-up, Less taiL-hsppy Black edition of the SLS.
在维多利亚时代，人们会以“尊贵奢华的泛欧大陆游”方式
In Victorian times,people would come through Venice
前往威尼斯旅行
on what was called "the grand tour",
这就是为什么我选择了这款奔驰的原因
so that's why I've gone for the Mercedes,
因为它是游览欧洲大陆的终极豪华交通工具
because it is the ultimate grand tourer.
嗯哼。你的奔驰还不是最终极的选择，因为我挑选了这辆法拉利F12.
Mmm-hmm. Except, it isn't the ultimate because this is, the Ferrari F12.
不，不。你的这辆马力太大了
No, no. That's too powerful.
-马力太大？ -是的马力过大。
-Too powerful? -It is too powerful.
我说过了，它...是的！
I said that... It is!
你居然在节目上说这种话，你让我...（傻笑）
You did say it on the programme and I thought then... (LAUGHS)
你了解这点吗？我能用到这辆车的所有动力
You see this? I will be able to use all of the power.
然后呢？
Yes?
也就是说你不能用尽你法拉利的全部动力
In that, you will not be able to use all of the power
因为你会和一根电线杆亲密接触，然后结束掉你本次的自驾之旅
because you'll end up halfway up a telegraph pole.
不，我会用到我全部的动力
No, I'll be able to all of the power
以及比你多得多的动力，这就是关键所在
but there will be more power than you've got, that's all that's about.
一次奢华的泛欧大陆游需要搭配强大的动力
A grand tourer should be powerful
-以及全身涂抹奶油身材火辣的女郎和...-呃...
-and creamy and grunty and... -Uh...
这货有622匹的强劲动力，这可不是一辆手推车
Six hundred and twenty-two horsepower,it's not a wheelbarrow.
-我这货有730马力！比你大 -我知道。
-Seven hundred and thirty! It's more. -I know.
哈蒙德！
Hammond!
让我们穿越意大利，行吗，开始我们的完美之旅
Let's just go across Italy, shall we,in our grand tourers?
好吧，好吧
Yes. Yes.
我的车会快得让你这货看起来像个娘炮
I'll go quickly, you big girl.
（狼嚎）
(SCREAMING)
（傻笑）噢，天啊！
(LAUGHING) Oh, God!
噢，这动力真是太强劲了！
Oh, that's a lot of power!
可能太强劲了点！不，还不算太强。
Maybe that's too much!No, it's not too much.
杰瑞米这回成了胆小鬼。他的只是足够而已
Jeremy's being a wuss. It's just enough.
实际上现在我不需要用到全部动力，
It's just I don't need to use all of it right now.
我只需要用到一点点，大概只有这么多
I'm going to use a bit less.Maybe this much of it.
换档速度简直惊人
The changes from that gearbox are incredible.
这车配备了一台双离合变速器。事实上
It's a double clutch gear box.In actual fact,
这货和杰瑞米的那台SLS的变速箱没啥区别
it's exactly the same unit as in Jeremy's Mercedes SLS.
只是法拉利装上了自家特有的
It's just Ferrari have put their own mapping,
控制单元匹配这台特殊的变速箱而已
their own computer control on this particular one.
所有参数都已被设定好，当你换档时
And it's set up so that when you change,
它会控制引擎转速使得动力汹涌而来
it spikes the engine revs so it surges when you change.
天啊！
Dear God!
这样的车身不只是好看那么简单
This body isn't just pretty,
它被雕琢成这样用来最大限度压榨下压力
it's been sculpted to maximise the air flowing over it to generate down force
以便把车身吸附在地面上
to stick it to the road.
奔驰过去制造过很多黑色系列车型
There have been a number of Black Special Edition Mercs in the past
所有黑色版本都一个鸟样，非常可怕，确实如此。不可驾驭
and almost all of them have been,well, dreadful, really. Undriveable.
它们都有一个通病那就是扭矩过大。所以每当你踩下油门
They generated too much torque.So every time you put your foot down,
那感觉就像它们想把自己撕成碎片
it felt like they were trying to tear themselves apart.
你会赞同我的这种说法，感觉就像它会把前方的一切事物
You'd be going along and it'd be sucking birds
比如鸟啊，树啊，松鼠啊之类的东西吸进引擎
and trees and squirrels into the engine
在撕碎道路的同时疯狂排出柏油和沥青的碎片
and then ripping up the road and hurling chunks of tarmac out of the back
那感觉简直就是...不可理喻
and it was just... They were ridiculous.
但这回，梅赛德斯终于变聪明了
This, though, Mercedes has been clever
因为，没错，它的马力确实比标准版SLS更大
because, yes, it generates more power than a standard SLS
但是扭矩却降低了11牛米。所以现在...
but 1 1 fewer torques. So now...
当你踩下油门，它会把这个动作全部转变成增长的车速
You put your foot down, it translates that action into speed,
而不再是破坏。
not destruction.
噢，你是不可能击败这台V8的！
Oh, but you can't beat a V8!
我想说，是的，那台V12确实很不错。但是这台V8更优秀
I mean, yes, a V12 is nice.But a V8 is nicer.
这是事实
It just is.
我刚说你不可能击败这台V8
I'm just ssying you can't best s V8.
喔，我喜欢V12，我就是喜欢一台庞大强劲，又带一点点躁动的V12
Oh,I like V12,I do like a big powerful,slightly angry 12.
（羡艳的笑声）那确实是一辆好车。
(LAUGHS) That's a great car, that.
（偷笑）这真是...你只是简单的轻点油门
(CHUCKLES) It's...You just give it a little poke,
“抱歉，打扰一下，请问能不...啊！”（尖叫）
"Excuse me, could you..." (SCREAMS)
这车真是太疯狂了！
That is insane!
哈蒙德：我真是太兴奋了
HAMMOND: I was veryhappy.
随后，让我感到意外的杰瑞米突然驶向了一个
And therefore s bit surprised when Jeremy suddenly veered off
古老的意大利小镇
towsrd some oLd ItsLisn town.
（教堂钟声）
(BELL TOLLING)
就是这里了
There it is.
-什么？那个？-是的
-What? That?-Yeah.
那就是罗密欧和朱丽叶里那个著名的阳台
That is the actual balcony from Romeo and JuLiet.
-好吧。我有几点想说。-什么？
-Yeah. Couple of points.-What?
我驾驶着一辆法拉利，在这样一个美好的天气，身处意大利
I've got a Ferrari,it's a beautiful day, I'm in Italy.
你却傻望着一个故事里虚构的阳台发呆...故事里的！
You're looking at a balcony that was in a story... Story!
而且你说过对莎士比亚从来都不感冒
Made up by a man who you said you don't like.
我确实不喜欢莎士比亚，但这里是...看啊！
I hate William Shakespeare but it's...Come on!
这不是真的，这只是个故事。一切都是虚构的
It's not real, it's a story.It was pretend.
你在进行一次欧洲游，你要见识一些名胜
You're on a tour of Europe,you need to see stuff.
我是在进行一次欧洲游，在一辆法拉利里，
I'm on a tour of Europe, in a Ferrari,
但我现在却没在驾驶法拉利
except I'm not in a Ferrari,
我现在站在这对着一座破房子发傻
I'm standing here looking at an old building.
幸运的是，一大群意大利top gear粉丝把杰瑞米团团围住
Happily, a big crowd of ItaLian Top Gear fans then stopped him
让他不能一览某座剧院的风采，这使得我们又回到了旅途中来
from getting into some oLd theatre so we couLd get back on the motorwsy.
如果因为杰瑞米去看某个傻大粗的意大利破房子
If he's going to ruin this road trip
而破坏了这次旅行，那我真的会...
by stopping off to look at old things that don't move, I'll...
克拉克森：我应该牢记这一点的，当然
CLARKSON: I should've remembered, of course,
哈蒙德对任何人文的事物都不感冒
Hammond isn't going to want to do anything cultural
而且他也对任何有意思的美食不感兴趣
and he isn't going to want to eat anything interesting.
感觉像和一个老年痴呆一起旅行似的
It's like travelling around with a garden chair.
于是我决定再调戏他一番
I therefore decided to annoy him some more.
-哈蒙德？-又有啥事？
-Hammond?-What?
我们从这里拐出去吧？
Shall we turn off here?
什么，现在？为啥又要拐出去？
What, now? Why would we?
因为我厌倦了在高速上傻走直线，我想换条路走走
Well, because I'm bored of driving on motorways,
I want to go on other roads.
你是想去看另一堆破砖烂瓦
Is there an old pile of bricks
或者神话故事里的无聊东西吗？
or a gate that once featured in a fairy tale down here?
不，不。我只是想找条更有趣的路而已
No, no.It's driving but just on nice roads.
我们不会再看些奇幻古堡之类的东西了吧？
We're not going to look at Hansel and Gretel's handbag or something?
克拉克森：事实上，我们正前往意大利湖
CLARKSON: In fsct, we were heading for the ItaLian Lakes,
这是一颗闪耀在我们这次旅途王冠上的璀璨明珠
a sparkLing jeweL in the goLden crown of our perfect journey.
很快我意识到今天的这车和这天气似曾相识
And soon I reaLised that cars Like these on days Like these
没错，正和意大利任务那期的情况一样
have been used before,at the beginning of The Italian Job.
我意识到应该放首歌来搭配现在的气氛
I know just the music we need for this bit of our drive.
来首蒙罗的老歌。
（麦特·蒙罗，二十世纪英国流行歌手。擅长翻唱经典老歌）
Cue the Monro.
（歌曲：这样的一天，麦特·蒙罗演唱）
(ON DAYS LIKE THESE BY MATT MONRO PLAYING)
哈蒙德：喔，这景色真是美极了
HAMMOND: Ooh, this is pretty,
从我这辆意大利超跑里往外看
looking at all of these Italian things from my Italian grand touring supercar.
我们进隧道的时候要格外小心
We just have to be careful that if we go into a tunnel,
以防撞上那些推土机（讽刺旁边车道的慢车）
we don't hit a bulldozer.
克拉克森：噢，这真的是...噢！
CLARKSON: Oh, thst's just... Oh!
这感觉太棒了
This is just magnificent.
但很快转向的问题接踵而至
But soon the real resaon for turning off became apparent.
因为道路变得越来越崎岖
As the rosds became more twisty,
法拉利变得越来越难驾驭
the Ferrari was becoming more of s handfuL.
噢-噢！噢！
Oh-ho! Oh!
呃，确实需要小心一点对待这730匹的马力
Uh, just need to be a bit careful about unleashing 730 brake horsepower.
这车的马力比一辆F1赛车还大，我突然意识到了这点
It's actually more than an F1 car and I'm conscious of that right now.
（呻吟）救命！噢！
(GROANS) Help! Oh!
噢！好的。
Oh! Yeah.
我一点也不紧张
I wasn't scared.
我一点也不怀疑那辆法拉利确实比这辆奔驰更快
I have no doubt that the Ferrari is faster than this
但这辆驾驶起来更舒服，因为它不会让你感到紧张
but this is just nicer to drive'cause it's less frightening.
哈蒙德：在这辆F12里，法拉利为你提供了一切
HAMMOND: With the F12, Ferrari have given you everything you need
能为你增添驾驶乐趣的配置
to have an incredible drive
同时也会把你卷入巨大的麻烦
or get yourself into a very great deal of trouble.
如果让一位赛车手来驾驶这辆车他会告诉你
Get a racing driver in this car and he will tell you,
“是的，这是一辆真正的跑车”
"Yes, that is a real car."
这车不是为那些经常混迹高尔夫球场
It's not been tamed for people to park at the golf course
或者酒吧的人所设计的
and talk about in the bar.
这车和标准版SLS的差别让人惊叹
It's amazing how different this is to the standard SLS,
标准版SLS车尾状态极其不稳定
which would be wobbling its bottom all over everywhere.
但这辆不会，因为它有一套独特的电子差速器
This isn't, because of its eLectronic differential.
你可以把它看成一辆保时捷GT3
You can think of it really like a Porsche GT3,
轻盈，扎实，精准，所有这些特性集于一身
lightened, hard,focused, on it, built for this.
这辆SLS的表现就好像是
The SLS behaving like this is like
让艾迪·伊扎德（喜剧演员）出演莎翁的戏剧《理查德三世》，这简直是...
Eddie Izzard doing Richard III, it's...
这奇怪的感觉就像你看的一出哑剧
It's almost weird to watch a pantomime character
突然变得非常容易理解
become so straight.
很奇怪但又很精彩
Weird and yet brilliant.
终于，我们来到了今晚住宿的地点
Eventually,we reached our overnight halt
我和那很有人文气质的同事一起享用晚餐
and I went for supper with my cuLtured coLLeague.
克拉克森：你说你喜欢湖区是啥意思？
CLARKSON: What do you mean you prefer the Lake District?
哈蒙德：这里很漂亮，确实如此
HAMMOND: Well, this is beautiful.It is.
-说实话，在我看来...
-这里比德文特湖更漂亮（英格兰湖泊，位于英格兰国家公园）
-And to be honest, for me...
-More beautiful than Derwentwater.
加尔达湖甚至不是这里最美的湖，但你看啊！
Garda's not even the prettiest lake and look at it!
这里确实很美。但如果面积能缩小75%
It's very lovely.Just scale it down to 75% of that
再加上细雨做点缀以及...
and then introduce a bit of drizzle and...
-凯西克也在湖区吗？
（英格兰坎布里亚郡的一个集镇。德文特湖以北，靠近巴森怀特湖和湖区国家公园）
-哦，是的
-Is Keswick in the Lake District?
-Ooh, yeah.
克拉克森：你在凯西克是看不到这些食物的。你以前见过吗？
CLARKSON: What you don't get in Keswick are these. Have you had one?
-从没见过。 -尝个辣椒。试试
-No. -Have a pepper. Eat.
吃吧。尝尝。你会喜欢它的
Eat. Eat it. Go on, you'll like it.
我不是很喜欢
I don't like it.
（笑）
(LAUGHS)
克拉克森：之后我们决定玩个我们喜欢的游戏
CLARKSON: Then we thought we'd play our favourite game.
他手里拿着一份法拉利选配价目表
He's got the Ferrari options pricelist there
我会猜猜那些配置都值多少钱
and I'm going to guess how much they cost.
这里有一大串选配目录
There are quite a lot of options available.
挑一些说来听听
Pick some.
好的。碳纤维比赛座椅
Okay. Racing seats with carbon fibre.
我不确定，600英镑（5963人民币）？
I don't know, 600 quid?
5184英镑（51528人民币）
£5184.
-我猜的有点点低。 -是的
-I was a bit under. -Yeah.
还有碳纤维轮毂罩，车轮上的，你知道，就是在...
But carbon fibre wheel caps,on the tyres, you know, on the...
-什么，防尘罩？ -是的
-What, dust caps? -Yeah.
碳纤维防尘罩？十英镑吧（99人民币）
Carbon fibre dust caps? Tenner.
480英镑（4771人民币）。我认为还是很便宜的
£480. I thought that was cheap.
-什么，就四个防尘罩？ -是的
-What, for four dust caps? -Yeah.
480镑？
£480?
有杯托吗？
Are the cup holders standard?
有碳纤维杯托选装配件
There is a carbon fibre cup holder you can get.
-一个碳纤维杯托？ -是的，你知道，就是用来放杯子的...
-A carbon fibre cup holder? -Yeah, you know, it pops in...
好吧，兰博基尼盖拉多上的这玩意价格在600英镑左右（5964人民币）
Well, they were £600 on a Lamborghini Gallardo a while back,
所以我猜法拉利上面值1000英镑（9940人民币）
so I'll go a thousand.
2112英镑（20993人民币），没错，真是太惊人了
£2112. Yeah, this is amazing.
事实上，这辆车才是最便宜的选配
Really, the car is the cheapest option.
哈蒙德：隔天，在我们研究地图之后意外发现
HAMMOND: The next day,we consulted a map and realised
离我们所在地不远的地方就坐落着目前F1赛历上均速最高的赛道...
we were just a spit from the fastest Grand Prix track on the calendar...
蒙扎
Monza.
速度的殿堂
The Cathedral of Speed.
因为这里能把速度开到如此之快
Because it's so fast,
我决定抛弃法拉利换上更快的
I've ditched the Ferrari and upped the ante
帕加尼风神
to this Pagani Huayra,
依旧是一台V12引擎但是配备了两台涡轮
still a V12 but now with two turbos.
因为在这里你需要火箭一般的速度
'Cause what you need here is a missile.
我选择了一辆保时捷Cayman S
I've gone for a Porsche Cayman S.
-你做了一个愚蠢的决定。 -不，我没有
-You're just being obtuse. -I'm not.
就是愚蠢的决定。你选择了保时捷
You are. You've gone for a Porsche
但你却没有选择911.这就是愚蠢
so you can not go for a 911.It's just annoying.
这辆比911更优秀
This is better than a 911.
-它不如911！911比这货强。-不是你想的那样
-It isn't! A 911 is better than that. -It isn't.
-因为911的引擎在这里。-没错。
-Because the 911 has its engine here. -Yes.
-这辆是中置引擎。-因为它不是911
-This is mid-engine. -Because it isn't a 911.
-不！-它更棒！
-No! -It's better!
听着，如果我们是在卡德维尔公园赛道，或者莱顿赛道（都是英国本土赛道）
Listen,if we were driving around Cadwell Park, Lydden Hill...
-是的。-弯又多又急，没错！
-Yeah. -Nippy and fizzy, yes!
但这里是蒙扎。你需要强大的动力
But not here at Monza. You need power.
你或许只注意到了这条
You're just hung up on this
-又长又直的大直道。-没错
-great big long straight. -Yes.
但在那之后的某些地方一定有弯道
But there must be a corner down there somewhere,
否则你不会出现在赛道的另一端
otherwise you wouldn't be able to get down there again.
这里一定有...事实上这里有两个弯道
There has to be...In fact there've got to be two corners.
-是啊，天才，这里有两个弯道。-是的
-Yes, genius, that's two corners. -Yeah.
你真有才。你知道吗？
Brilliant. Do you know what?
帕加尼风神过弯的本事也是数一数二的
The Pagani Huayra goes around corners really incredibly well.
你不会相信它过弯的速度有多惊人
You will not believe how fast this goes around corners.
-好吧。-我的车更棒
-Okay. -It's a lot better.
克拉克森：事实确是如此，我不喜欢保时捷
CLARKSON: It's true,I don't like Porches
并且我也不喜欢驾驶它们的人
and I don't much like the people who drive them,
特别是他们之中有两个叫詹姆士和理查德的家伙
especially the ones called James and Richard.
我也不喜欢最初的Cayman
I didn't much like the original Cayman, either,
我把它叫做鸟车
I called it the Cockster.
在这车身上还有两样我不喜欢的东西
And there are one or two things that I don't much like about this.
一个是设计风格，比如这车长得太像911了
The styling, for example,I think it looks too like a 911.
还有这个座椅，肩部支撑太狭窄
And then there's the seats,the shoulder bolsters are too narrow.
所以如果你有一副和我一样伟岸的肩膀，
So, if you're broad-shouldered and hunky, like me,
你开这车就会觉得很难受
you're getting sort of squashed all the time.
但除此之外，这车的一切都很完美
However, the rest of it is absolutely sublime.
这车有一套自适应悬挂系统，这就意味着
You've got these adaptive dampers,which means that it rides
它的驾乘感、操控感、转向感都和最棒的超级跑车毫无二致
and handles and steers like the very best supercars.
但是其中最棒的还是它的引擎。一台3.4升水平对置六缸发动机
But the best thing is the engine.A 3.4-litre flat six.
这台机器毫无瑕疵
There's just no thing about it that's wrong.
在任何时候它都能发出这种...你能听见
And all the time it makes this... You can hear that
那种低沉，铿锵有力的声浪
deep, reassuring noise,
这就像是把理查德·伯顿塞进你的后备箱
（理查德·伯顿，英国影史上的巨星，尤善演莎士比亚笔下人物）
it's like having Richard Burton in the boot,
他会无休止的赞美你的发型，
endlessly complimenting you on your hair
你的着装，你的驾驶技术
and your clothes and your driving style.
噢，我的天！这真的太快了！
Oh, my God! That is so fast!
噢，我的天！
Oh, my God!
230km/h，240km/h，250km/h
230, 240, 250,
260km/h
260 kilometres an hour.
270km/h！我勒个亲娘
270! Oh, dear God.
噢！我已经被自己的这速度吓得屁滚尿流了
Oh! I scared the crap out of myself then.
天啊...
Holy sh...
老天爷！
Oh, my God!
真是台厉害的机器！
What a machine!
蒙扎就是速度的代名词
Monza is all about speed
而帕加尼风神除了拥有速度之外也再无其他
and a Pagani Huayra is about that and very little else.
6.3升，V12，双涡轮
6.3-litre, v12, twin turbos.
货真价实，巨大的动力
Truly, enormously powerful.
进弯，宽大的轮胎提供了强大的抓地力
Turning in, immense grip from those fat tyres.
我有空气，主动空气制动系统帮我时刻保持在赛道内
I have aero, active aero keeping me planted on the track.
这套系统用来保证这车完美运行，而不像那些中看不中用的花架子
These things are built to work as well,they're not some fragile trailer queen.
我驾驶的这台车已经有8万6千公里的里程了
This car I'm in has done 86,000 kilometres.
我猜这些里程当中没多少是温柔驾驶的
And I'm guessing not many of them were gentle.
法拉利或许很出色，但它肯定不如帕加尼这般完美
The Ferrari would've been good at this but not as good as the Huayra.
哈蒙德的问题在于他的速度太快了
The problem is Hammond is going too fast,
他没有好好品味这条赛道的光荣以及历史积淀
he's not savouring this glorious,historical track.
他只是快速的掠过这条赛道，像猪八戒吃人参果一样糟蹋美食
He's just wolfing it down,like a dog wolfs down a steak.
（哇呜）
(GOBBLES)
而我现在做的则是细嚼慢咽，慢慢品尝每一口美味
What I'm doing is masticating,enjoying every mouthful.
哈蒙德：当杰瑞米驾驶着他选择的错误车辆在赛道上龟速行驶时
HAMMOND: As Jeremy crawled round in his wrong car,
我早就开到维修区等着他回来了
I was waiting for him to get back to the pits.
还要等很久他才能回来，是吗？
He's going to be a while, isn't he?
趁着他还在龟行，让我为各位介绍一下帕加尼的内饰
While he's gone, let me show you the interior of the Pagani.
这值得一观
It's worth seeing.
他们希望坐在这车里让人感觉独一无二，而我确信他们成功地做到了这一点
They want it to feel special in here and I think they've succeeded.
他们真的把思想融入其中，让它感觉很独特
They've really put thought into this,making it feel special.
这里的档位连接，所有的这些部件
This gear linkage here,all these parts,
一共67个零件构成了这部分独特的透视结构
there's 67 components have gone into making that
能让你清楚地看见它是怎么工作的
in that skeleton form,so you can see it working.
关于用料也很讲究，用的都是货真价实的材质
And the materials, too,it's all genuine,
大量的碳纤维，真皮，以及铝合金
a lot of real carbon fibre,real leather. And the aluminium,
每一件你所见到的铝合金部件都不是简单铸造而成
every single aluminium component you can see in here isn't cast,
而是通过一整块铝锭铣削而成
it's milled from a single piece,a single billet, a lump of aluminium.
所有这一切都意味着它给人的感觉就和它的价格一样高贵
All of which means it feels as expensive as it is.
我喜欢这辆车。他还没回来，是吗？
I like this car.He's not back yet, is he?
这是世界上唯一一条拥有两个lesbos弯道的赛道（一句废话- -#）
第一个弯非常急
This is the only track in the world with two lesbos, the first one's quite tight,
第二个弯能让你瞬间失禁
second one, though,you can really hang your arse out.
就是这里
There it is.
这是12气缸的全貌。让我们数数看，这会很费时间...
It's 12 cylinders in total.Let's count them, it'll pass the time.
1,2...喔，我数得有点快了，不妨数的久一点
One, two... Oh, I'm going too quickly,might as well make it last.
3...噢，等等。哦！
Three... Oh, hang on. Oh!
你现在一定有这种感觉了...
You must be feeling now...
-什么感觉？-...你选了一辆错误的车
-What? -...that you brought the wrong car.
让我给你读一段东西，如果可以的话。描述这辆保时捷的
Let me read you something, if I may.Talking about this.
“这辆车的过弯平衡性近乎完美，
"The car's cornering balance is near perfect,
具有接近中性并且有预见性地油门平衡特点
"neutral but unerringly predictable on a balanced throttle
如果在你开始释放前轮的横向载荷之前
"and biased ever so slightly towards understeer
轻收一点油门
"if you throttle up before you begin easing
本车就会带有一点轻微的转向不足特性”（鬼知道翻译的对不对）
"the lateral load out of the front tyres."
这不是我说的，这是汽车杂志原文
Not my words, the words of Autocarmagazine.
哇呜！你念的这些文字是什么意思？
Wow! What do those words actually mean?
-我不清楚 -我也不理解
-I've no idea. -Me, neither.
但是我要回到赛道上去试试所谓的
But I'm going to go back out there now and throttle up
“释放前轮横向载荷之前轻收油门”会发生什么事
before I've eased the lateral load out of the front tyres and see what happens.
-是嘛！-这就是我要干的
-Yeah! -That's what I'm going to do.
我一点也不理解那些东西是啥意思。乱七八糟
I have no idea what any of that means.I haven't a clue.
好的！收油门
Right! Throttle up.
喔，你瞧见了吧？
Oh, now you see?
这会产生甩尾
Now, that's just a spin.
看吧，汽车杂志，这会转向过度
Now, you see, Autocar, that's oversteer.
有时候你读一些道路测试的文章时你不禁会发出慨叹，“这写的都是些什么东西啊？”
Sometime you read road tests and you do think, "What are you on about?"
这是一辆不错的车，它能把你吓得屁滚尿流
It's a really nice car and you can get the arse out.
哈蒙德：终于
HAMMOND: Finally.
-还是假装这车很有乐趣？-是的
-Still pretending to have fun? -Yeah.
-呃，这车会把你吓得失禁吗？-会怎么样？
-Will, uh, will Poo be like this? -Will what?
屁滚尿流，当我们到达目的地的时候
Poo, when we go there.
哦，波城？
Oh, Pau?
你知道我最喜欢的地方吗？
Do you know my favourite bit?
-哈蒙德：是的，是的。-你能...
-HAMMOND: Yes. Yes.-You could...
保时捷通过这里的时候，它就像闪电一般迅速（阿斯卡里弯）
The Porsche through there,it's just a streak of lightning.
没有任何车能比它更快
Nothing is faster than that.
绝对没有。也没有任何车...在这个弯比它快
Nothing is.Nothing's faster... Or through there.
是的，你有点语无伦次了。它确实很快。它是辆很快的小跑车
Yes, you're getting a bit carried away.It's fast.
It's a quick little car.
说实话，它在居民区会更快
To be honest,it's more at home in this bit here.
你能“哦，看啊！”驶过商店
You could "Oh, look!" past the shops
还有“噢，还有这学校和超市”
and "Oh, there's a school and a supermarket."
这些地方才是这车的归宿。不是在这条赛道上
And that's really where it belongs.Not here.
-你错了。-我没错
-You're wrong.-I'm not wrong.
哈蒙德，我用任何你喜欢的东西做赌注和你打赌，保时捷更快
Hammond, I bet you anything you like that around here the Porsche is faster.
杰瑞米，那真是...
Jeremy, that's...
-好吧！-打赌输的人要说
-Okay!-Whoever loses has to say,
“我爱詹姆斯·梅”
"I love James May."
输的人要对着镜头说这句话
They have to say that on television to a camera.
没问题
Fine.
你一定要对着摄像机镜头说“我爱詹姆斯·梅”
You actually have to go up to the camera and go, "I love James May."
没问题。我期待着听到你说出这句话
All right. Well, I look forward to hearing you say it.
噢，这里有两个lesmos弯
Oh, they're lesmos.
我本以为那里只有一个lesmos弯...没想到居然有两个...
I thought there was lesbo one and...It's lesmo...
马丁·布伦德尔一定患了伤风
（马丁·布伦德尔，英国前F1车手，现天空体育评论员）
Martin Brundle must have had a cold.
好的
Right.
（意大利语）
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
开始了
And we are away.
（打呵欠）
(YAWNS)
噢，天啊！这真是令人尴尬
Oh, God! This is just embarrassing
难道我的成就感就是靠击败他这样的人才能实现的？
because where's going to be my sense of achievement when I thrash him?
克拉克森：有一条关于车的金科玉律
CLARKSON: There is a point with cars
当一辆车马力越大速度越高时
where they become so powerful and so fast
它就会让人越难以驾驭以及越紧张
they become too hectic and too frightening.
这就是那辆...（￥#&￥%！）的问题所在（火星语～）
That's the problem with the...(MOCKINGLY) Huayra.
通过第一个lesmo弯
Through the first of the lesmo corners,as it turns out.
克拉克森：我知道这听起来有点愚蠢
CLARKSON: I know it sounds silly but once you go
但当你驾驶一辆马力超过500-550的跑车时，你会变得更慢
beyond 500-550 horsepower,you end up driving the car more slowly.
听起来很奇怪但确是事实
It's weird but it's true.
从没有人做过这样愚蠢的事情
Never has there been a more stark example of
竟然拿着菜刀去参加枪战
bringing a knife to a gunfight.
保时捷在这条赛道上，我能保证每一圈都把它牢牢的留在赛道内
The Porsche, around here,I'm absolutely pinning it everywhere.
它不会让我觉得难以驾驭和紧张，驾驶它很轻松
It doesn't worry me,it's not frightening, it's easy.
而那货，就...
That thing, though...
好吧，走着瞧
Well, we shall see.
我的话会得到证明，而哈蒙德会对着镜头说“我爱詹姆斯·梅”
My case will be proven and he will be saying, "I love James May."
我看见了270公里的时速
That's 270 I saw there.
他不会看见这么惊人的数字
He won't see anything like that.
噢
Oh.
我听见了小矮人靠近终点线的声音
I hear the sound of an approaching midget.
全油门
Fully on the power.
准备，保持...
Ready, steady...
冲线！
And across the line!
2分14秒8
Two minutes, 14.8.
我们通常管这叫2分15秒
We'll call it 2:15.
接下来轮到Cayman登场
Then it was the Cayman's turn.
（意大利语）
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
说实话，我对此一点也不感到高兴
Really, I am taking no pleasure in this.
但他需要在此上一课
But he does need to learn a lesson,
你不能以个人喜好来判断一辆车的好坏
that you can't just go making stupid claims about a car
这简直太愚蠢了
just 'cause you like it.
不，说真的，对于那辆车...我只需要用一个煮蛋计时器
No, seriously, that thing round...I could be using an egg timer.
他怎么会认为他能靠那辆车击败我？
How does he imagine he can possibly make up enough time?
不管他认为他的技术有多好
No matter how good he thinks he is in it.
显然，他不可能...算了
Clearly, it's not going to... Anyway.
-你说啥？-你！
-You what? -Mate!
你怎么在...你不是在...
Where... Why aren't you...
我没说过我去开车
I didn't say I'd be driving it.
那谁在开那辆车？
Well, who is?
据说开车的是Stig，事实确实如此
Well, some say it's The Stig, and it is.
你什么时候说过我要开车了吗？没有
Did you at any point say I had to drive it? No.
你什么时候有说过你会用Stig了吗？
Did you at any point say you were going to use The Stig?
你为什么不用呢？
Why would you not?
因为我认为不论从哪个角度来看
Because I think in every possible definition,
在任何规则下，你这都是作弊行为
in every set of rules, it's cheating.
噢，他来了
Oh, here he is.
哈蒙德：2分13秒2
HAMMOND: 2:13:2.
-2分13秒2. -是的
-2:13:2. -Yes.
你的成绩是2分14秒8. 所以Stig比你快一点几...
You were 2:14:8. So he's one point...
所以，各位看见了，女士们先生们，保时捷，正如我说的那样
So, there you are, ladies and gentlemen,the Porsche is, as I said,
比（￥#……%#）...要快
faster than the, uh...(MOCKINGLY) Huayra.
所以它是更好的选择
And therefore was a more sensible choice of car.
-不。是Stig比我快。-什么？
-No. The Stig is faster than me.-What?
但Stig在没有爆炸的情况下，会比任何人都快
But The Stig is faster than everyone,that's the point of The Stig,
这是Stig的问题
if he wasn't he'd explode.
克拉克森：当我们开着奔驰和法拉利离开蒙扎之后
CLARKSON: As we left Monza in the Mercedes and the Ferrari,
团队气氛变得很阴沉
the mood was glum.
这个大骗子
It's cheating.
克拉克森：但第二天早晨，当我们发现留宿小镇的名字时
CLARKSON: The next morning, however,Hammond cheered up
哈蒙德还是高兴了起来
when he discovered the name of the town where we'd stayed the night.
（窃笑）（BRA-女性内衣简写）
(BOTH SNIGGERING)
从Bra到法国南部里维埃拉
From Bra to the French Riviera,
我们可以走高速公路
we could've used the motorway.
但我们决定另走一条
But we decided instead
世界上最棒的
to use the finest switchback roads
盘山公路
in the world.
这就意味着
This meant ditching the Mercedes
我们将再次抛弃奔驰和法拉利
and the Ferrari
重新选车来面对接下来的挑战
and opting for these instead.
在这样的道路上
On a road like this,
你需要一辆身形小巧的高性能掀背钢炮
you need something small,you need a hot hatchback.
如果你选择一辆小钢炮
And if you're going to get a hot hatchback,
有什么理由不选择其中的王者？
why not get the king? This one.
高尔夫GTI
The Golf GTI.
我喜欢第一代GTI
I loved the Mk1
并且16气门的第二代GTI也不错
and the 16-valve Mk2 wasn't bad, either.
但是自那以后...我意思是虽然后继车型也不错
But since then...I mean, they weren't bad
但那种魔力消失了
but the magic went missing.
在这辆车上，第七代GTI，那种魔力又回来了
With this one, though, the Mk7,it is back.
这辆车能干任何事
This car can do everything.
工艺精湛，价格合理
It's well made, it's sensibly priced.
也很环保，配置丰富
It's economical, it's well-equipped.
有五个座位，还有一个大后备箱
It seats five, it's got a big boot.
但是抛开所有这一切，在外表之下
But strip all that away and underneath,
它的本质是一辆高性能掀背跑车
its DNA is hot hatchery.
（轮胎啸叫）
(TYRES SCREECHING)
两升涡轮增压引擎，220匹马力
Two-litre turbo engine, 220 horsepower
没有扭矩转向的状况发生
and no torque steer.
看看这个。大力制动，切入回头弯
Now, watch this. Foot hard down,going around a hairpin bend.
惊为天人
It's just astonishing.
这车的前差速器性能超乎你想象
The front diff on this is beyond belief.
哇呜！天啊，感觉真不错
Whoa! God, this is good.
这回他又选错了车
He's got it wrong again.
高尔夫GTI，确实是辆不错的车
The Golf GTI, it's a brilliant car,
可能是世界上最好的全能型车
it's probably the best all-rounder in the world.
但是...有一点
But that's... That's the point,
实际你并不需要全能车
an all-rounder is exactly what you don't need.
全能就意味着某些地方不可避免地作出妥协
An all-rounder is inevitably compromised.
我想要的只是一辆纯粹的钢炮
I just want pure distilled essence of hot hatch.
这意味着只有一款车适合我
And that means only one thing right now.
福特嘉年华ST
The Fiesta ST.
当福特顺利地制造出这款车时
When Ford put this car together,they assembled all the right bits
他们或许会想：“没错，这会是辆很棒的车”
and thought, "Yeah, I reckon that would be good."
我猜他们不会想到
I don't think they could possibly have known
这款车会成为多受追捧的一台小钢炮
quite how good it was going to turn out to be,
因为它太惊人了
because it's astonishing.
它确实比高尔夫GTI少了点马力
It's down on power compared to the Golf, yes.
但是它更小巧，这就意味着它更运动
But it's smaller, that's more hot hatch.
并且也更轻
And it's lighter,
这就说明它的推重比和高尔夫不分伯仲
which means the power-to-weight ratio is pretty much the same.
并且它十分灵活
And it's beyond nimble.
你随意给它一个转向
You start to just take liberties with it.
走出一条较宽的行车线
Deliberately running a line a little bit wide,
你会很兴奋地再把它给拽回来
so you get the pleasure of turning it back in.
（兴奋的笑）
(LAUGHS)
这感觉太棒了
It's superb.
这是我所驾驶过全世界最棒的小钢炮
It's the biggest grin-maker I think the world has ever seen.
在接下来的一个小村里，不可避免的
In the next village, though, inevitably,
杰瑞米决定寻摸点食物
Jeremy decided we should get something to eat.
你为啥不享用你的午餐
Why aren't you eating your lunch?
我不喜欢蒜泥
I don't like pesto.
-什么？-我不喜欢蒜泥
-What?-I don't like pesto.
-为什么？-这只是一滩浆糊而已
-Why not?-It's just bits.
克拉克森：还有一个更好的理由解释为什么我们需要停下来
CLARKSON: There was, however,a very good reason why we'd stopped.
你必须说出那句话。你打赌输了，要认赌服输
You've got to say it.You lost the bet, you've got to say it.
我不要说那句话
I'm not saying it.
你必须说出那句话
You've got to say it.
我正大光明的赢了你。保时捷比你快
I beat you fair and square.The Porsche was faster.
-这不公平。你作弊了。-说出那句话
-It wasn't fair. You cheated.-Say it.
（喃喃细语）
(MOUTHING)
什么？
What?
（含糊其辞）
(MUMBLING)
（咳嗽）...詹姆斯·梅
(COUGHING) ...James May.
-说完了。-不行。要说清楚
-There.-No. Say it so it's audible.
我...爱詹姆斯·梅
I...love James May.
克拉克森：干完了正事，我们回到了各自的车上
CLARKSON: With that done,we got back in our cars.
当你想象身处美国旅行时，你会自然的想到纪念碑山谷
（纪念碑山谷：美国亚利桑那州以北，犹他州以南，
科罗拉多高原一部分，美国荒凉西部的标志形象）
When you think of an American road trip,you think of Monument Valley,
州际公路笔直延伸至漫无边际的远方
that road spearing off into the distance.
你可以把这里想象成欧洲版的纪念碑山谷
Well, this is Europe's equivalent of Monument Valley.
这里可能是本次旅行到目前为止少数几个我喜欢的路段之一
This might just be my favourite bit of our trip so far.
这车、这风景
The car, the place.
太完美了
This is perfect.
克拉克森：这片神奇的土地可能是造物主
CLARKSON: When God was making this part of the world,
为小钢炮创造出来的。这就是它存在的理由
it was for hot hatchbacks.That's what it's for.
不幸的是，即便如此
Unfortunately, however,
我们在阿尔卑斯山路中的撒欢行为
our headlong charge down the Alps
还是伴随着大陆的终结戛然而止
was halted because we ran out of land.
（叹气）
(EXHALES)
-唔,这里。-什么？
-Mmm, that. -What?
好吧，前面就是蒙特卡洛。如果我们继续开着大众和福特进城
Well, it's Monte-Carlo.If we drive into there
他们会以流浪汉的名义拘捕我们
in a Volkswagen and a Ford,they'll arrest us for vagrancy.
确实如此
That's a good point.
-我想说，军火贩子在那都没事... -是的。
-I mean, you can be an arms dealer... -Yeah.
...但是你不能开着福特嘉年华进城
...but you can't drive around in a Fiesta.
-这是底线。 -我们又要换车了
-There's a limit. -We're going to need to switch.
克拉克森：为了掩盖屌丝气质，我们选择了这两辆车
CLARKSON: For posing,these were the cars we selected.
哈蒙德挑了一辆兰博基尼敞篷版Aventador
A Lamborghini Aventador Roadster for Hammond
而我则挑了一台敞篷版布加迪威龙
and a Bugatti Veyron for me.
这可不是一辆普通版的威龙
Now, this is no ordinary Veyron,
这是一辆维特斯特别版超级运动型威龙
this is the Grand Sport Vitesse.
八升排量，16气缸引擎
Eight-litre, quad-cam W16.
极速能达到251英里每小时（404公里每小时）
Top speed 251 miles an hour
在顶棚拆掉的状态下
with no roof.
这里才是这车的栖息地
Here it is in its natural habitat.
我现在切到二档。用到了二档
I'm in second gear.I'm now using second gear
自从我开上这车以来第一次切到二档
for, well, the first time since I set off.
现在又回到一档
And back down to first.
这里的居民很神奇，他们早上十点钟
It is extraordinary that here men get up
从单身公寓里爬起来
from their bachelor pads at about 10:00,
开着用本应交给国家的税金买来的车出门
get into their cars that they bought using money they should have paid in tax
然后花一天的时间
and then spend all day
在大街上漫无目的地转来转去
driving round and round and round in circles.
这有啥意义？
Why?
哈蒙德：路人看我开着橘色兰博基尼驶过时
HAMMOND: People see me in my orange Lamborghini Aventador Roadster
会这么想“这是个有钱有势的大人物”
and think, "Yes.There's a man of potency and wealth."
过了两秒钟，他们看见我身后那辆布加迪威龙
And then two seconds later,they see that Bugatti Veyron
于是又会这么想“这是个更有钱有势的大人物”
and think, "There's a richer,more powerful man."
我为你感到遗憾，伙计
I'm sorry about this, mate,
但你再次选了一辆错误的车
but once again,you're in the wrong car.
我要纠正你关于“再一次”的措辞
I take issue with the "once again"
但是的，我承认这是我第一次选错车
but, yes, for the first time,I've got the wrong car.
（克拉克森傻笑）
(CLARKSON LAUGHS)
克拉克森：没人关注你，没人
CLARKSON: Nobody is looking at you,nobody.
哈蒙德：如果我花29万英镑（288万人民币）
HAMMOND: If I had spent £290000
在一辆兰博基尼身上用来绕着摩纳哥闲逛
on a Lamborghini to drive around Monaco
并且你出现在我的车里
and you turned up in that,
我宁愿直接把它开上墙
I'd just drive this into a wall.
这是全世界最拜金的地方
This is the snobbiest place on earth.
它让...
It makes...
它让洛杉矶在其面前如同北朝鲜般相形见绌
It makes Los Angeles look like North Korea.
这种势利的氛围也会
And this snobbery is an issue
体现在酒店服务生为你泊车时
when you try to get your car valet parked.
问题在于那个伙计刚刚在巴黎饭店门口停好了他的
The problem is that chap has just turned up outside the Hotel de Paris
法拉利加尼弗尼亚
in a Ferrari California.
法拉利最廉价的车型
The cheapest Ferrari there is.
虽然如此，看上去他很喜欢那辆车
Nevertheless, he likes it very much.
是的，车很漂亮。停那的样子确实不错
Yeah, and it's nice.And as a result, it's there.
-是吧？起来不错。 -没错
-Okay? 'Cause it looks good. -Yeah.
但仅仅一会的功夫
But in a minute,
一个哈萨克斯坦军火贩子就开着一辆更拉风的车停在了门口
a Kazakhstani arms dealer is going to arrive in a nicer car
而那辆法拉利就被服务生给挪走了
and the Ferrari is going to be taken away
泊到酒店另一边的多层停车场
and put in a multi-storey on the other side of Monaco.
哈蒙德：但我们停在这里的是
HAMMOND: But we pull up there
一辆布加迪威龙和一辆兰博基尼Aventador敞篷版
in a Bugatti Veyron and a Lamborghini Aventador Roadster,
你是说还有比这两台更棒的车会出现？
are you're saying something better is going to come along than that?
在摩纳哥，我打赌
In Monte-Carlo, I promise you,
肯定会有开着企业号航母来花天酒地的金主
someone would turn up inthe USS Enterprise
那时我们的车肯定会被挪到阴暗的角落里去
and our cars would be in the multi-storey.
这和你的车多昂贵没关系
It doesn't matter how good your car is,
服务生最终还是会把你的车给挪走
the valet parkers will ultimately take it away
因为总会有更拉风的神器出现
because something better always arrives.
肯定有种方法能解决这个问题。这是一次完美汽车之旅
There's got to be a way around this.This is the perfect motoring trip.
所以我们今天要找到一辆车停在那，
So we go and check in there, in a car,
-这是我们完美之旅的一部分... -是的
-on our perfect road trip...-Yeah.
...第二天当我们出来，我们的车必须还在门口
...we come out in the morning,it's still there.
这就是我们的目标
That's our challenge.
必须是辆非常特别的车
It's going to have to be pretty special.
噢，没错
Oh, yeah.
克拉克森：哈蒙德，最终选择了这辆车
CLARKSON: Hammond, however, opted to go
有史以来销量最高的车型
with one of the best-selling cars the world has ever seen.
福特T型车
A Model T Ford.
但我们马上面临了一个问题
And straightaway there was a problem.
我们不知道如何操纵它
We didn't know how it worked.
好吧，让我们瞧瞧这家伙
Right, now, look.
检查都有些什么东西
Let's list the things.
一共有...一共有三个踏板
There are... There's three pedals.
你是怎么...挡把在哪？这是档位吗？这是...
How do you... Where's the gear?Is this the gear? That's...
哈蒙德：噢，如果这是...这玩意感觉不像离合器
HAMMOND: Oh, if it's...I haven't got my foot on the clutch.
-这不是离合器。-好吧，这个...
-That isn't the clutch. -Well, then...
哪个是油门？
Which one's the accelerator?
这是油门。这居然不是踏板，我确定...
That's the accelerator.It isn't a pedal, I'm sure...
我怎么把脚放上去？
How am I going to get my foot up there?
-呃...该怎么做？ -好吧，启动引擎
-Um... What's that do? -Right, well, start it.
-（喇叭声） -这不是点火开关！
-(HORN HONKING) -That's not the starter!
克拉克森：最终，哈蒙德还是让这老家伙动了起来
CLARKSON: Eventually,Hammond did make it begin.
但接下来他意识到自己还不会让这老爷子停下来
But then we learned he didn't know how to make it stop.
噢，现在该怎么办？
Oh, now what have I done?
我们在加速！
We're going faster!
那不是手刹。停住。停下来。
That's not the handbrake.Stop it. Stop it.
-（尖叫声） -把它停下来！
-(SCREAMING) -Stop it now!
（两人尖叫）
(BOTH SCREAMING)
好的，前进
Right, forwards.
-等等。准备。-前进
-Hang on. Now, ready. -Forwards.
-这不是前进。-不，它没前进，对吧？
-That's not forwards. -No, it's not at all, is it?
停下来。让它停住
Stop it. Make it stop.
它没有要停的意思，你觉得呢？
It doesn't really want to, do you know?
停下！
Make it stop!
呃，杰瑞米，我们让整个摩纳哥都陷入了拥堵
Uh, Jeremy, we've held up Monaco.
-我们？ -瞧后面
-Have we? -Look.
噢，天啊
Oh, God.
不一会，我们就接近了目的地
Soon, however,we were nearing our destination.
我不是经常说这样的话，哈蒙德
It's not often I say this, Hammond,
但你这回确实天才了一把
but you have been a genius.
你从没说过这样的话
You have never said that.
因为如果我们不能驾驶这辆车
Because if we can't drive this,
我们用什么来击败巴黎酒店的服务生？
what chance do the valet parkers at the Hotel de Paris have?
没有了，这是我玩过最复杂的车
None, it's the hardest thing I've ever done.
克拉克森：他们会想把它挪走，但他们不会成功的
CLARKSON: They'll want to move this but they won't be able to.
（坏笑）
(LAUGHING)
-你好，先生。-你好，先生
-BonJour, monsieur. -Hello, sir.
熄火
Shut it down.
哈蒙德：交给你了
HAMMOND: All yours.
-你好。 -你好
-BonJour. -BonJour.
你好
BonJour.
克拉克森：接下来，看看服务生能不能搞定这车？
CLARKSON: So, would the valetstaff be successful?
（听不清）
(INAUDIBLE)
显然没有
No.
所以，我们做到了。这就是如何击败酒店服务生的办法
So, there we go.That is how to beat the valet parkers.
买一辆他们玩不转的车
Buy a car they can't drive.
没错，但问题又来了
Yes, but the problem is
今天我们将要
today we are going
从里维埃拉前往圣特鲁佩斯
down the French Riviera to Saint-Tropez
我不确定
and I'm not sure
我要开着这辆车去那里
I want to go in that.
我不确信这辆车能带着我们去任何地方
I'm not sure I'd actually go anywhere in it.
（引擎咆哮）
(ENGINE REVVING)
这是捷豹E型车
This is a Jaguar E-Type.
这是1962年款1系敞篷版
It's a 1962 Series 1 Roadster
配备一台血统纯正的3.8升直列六缸引擎
with the proper 3.8-litre straight six.
（引擎咆哮）
(ENGINE REVVING)
而且这车与其它任何一辆1962年款E型车都不同
And it's not just any 1962 E-Type.
这台是我的
It's mine.
我也想不出还有哪款车
And I can think of no car
比这车更适合今天这样的好天气
more perfect for a day like today.
喔，我能
Oh, I can.
因为我现在驾驶的是捷豹V8 F型
Because I am in a V8 F-Type.
这车比哈蒙德的那辆更快
This is faster than Hammond's E-Type.
同时也更舒适，更环保，更可靠
It's more comfortable,more economical, more reliable,
空调也更优秀
more air-conditioned.
甚至价格也只有8万6千英镑而已（85万人民币）
And even though it costs £86,000,
更实惠
it's cheaper.
起床了，法国佬
Wake up, Frenchies.
噢，快得和火箭一样
Oh, that's a racket.
你能听见我车尾那动听的排气声浪么？
Can you hear the exhausts from back there?
你把远在威尼斯的人都给吵醒了
They can hear them back in Venice.
克拉克森：从没哪辆车比我现在开的这辆
CLARKSON: Never has a car been more perfectly tailored to its environment
更适合这里的环境了
than this is here.
这是协和客机诞生的国度
This is where the jetset was invented.
我们正置身于一个捷豹的国度，我能感受到
We are in Jag country, I can feel it.
和这里任何一家餐厅的生意会持续火爆下去不同
Not a restaurant bill will have been paid around here for decades.
捷豹它来去匆匆，只留下两道轮胎印
Just Jaguar tyre marks where they've screeched away.
“抱歉，我回去取钱”
"I'm sorry.I'll pop off and get my wallet."
克拉克森：70年代有一部电视剧
CLARKSON: There used to be a TV series in the '70s
名叫“说服者”。主演是罗杰·摩尔和汤尼·寇蒂斯
（托尼·柯蒂斯：美国50年代老牌名演员）
called The Persuaders!with Roger Moore and Tony Curtis.
我耳边仿佛又响起了那首主题曲
And I'm hearing that music now.
（说服者，主题曲）
(THE PERSUADERS!THEMEPLAYING)
罗杰·摩尔和汤尼·寇蒂斯
Roger Moore, Tony Curtis,
驾驶着法拉利Dino和阿斯顿马丁DBS
whizzing about down here in a Ferrari Dino
飞驰而过
and an Aston Martin DBS,
侦破无数大案
solving many things,
打击犯罪拯救美女
punching men and saving womens.
哈蒙德：当我也在重温那段美妙的回忆时，我的同事又开始了...
HAMMOND: I was enJoying it, too.Until...
哈蒙德，这里有家毕加索艺术馆
Hammond, the Picasso museum's along here.
我们停下来欣赏欣赏吧
We could stop and have a look.
你认真的?我正驾驶着我的捷豹E型车
Really? I'm in a Jaguar,
沐浴在浪漫的法国南部风景中
my E-Type, in the south of France,
你却要我停下车去看一个
and you want me stop driving to look at a man
把耳朵画错位画家的画展？
whose ears are in the wrong place?
错了，你说的是梵高
No, that was Van Gogh.
毕加索是那个
Picasso's the one who puts eyes
画错眼睛的哥们
on the wrong side of somebody's head.
去吧，这是一次旅行。让我们看看画展
come on, it's a road trip.Let's look at some pictures.
哈蒙德：你明白你刚才说的是什么话么？
HAMMOND: Did you not hear what you just said?
“这是一次自驾游，让我们去看看画展”
"It's a road trip.Let's look at some pictures."
绝不！
No!
噢，为啥你这么不文艺？
Oh, why are you so uncultured?
在瑞昂莱潘，身材火辣的姑娘们
In Juan-les-Pins,where all the girls have
穿着设计别致的比基尼
carefully designed topless swimsuits
在海滩引诱着各路游客的目光
and racehorses they keep just for fun,
开个玩笑，哈哈哈哈（这是个冷笑话 — —#）
for a laugh, a-ha-ha,
我们停下车让哈蒙德享受些美食
we pulled over so Hammond could look at some food.
-怎么了？ -我不喜欢吃章鱼
-What now? -I don't like octopus.
这菜有问题么？
What's the matter with it?
-这个... -你想吃我的松露
-Well... -Do you want my truffles
配鸡蛋卷吗？
on an omelette?
我不喜欢松露。你把我的这次自驾游给毁了
Don't like truffles.You are ruining this trip for me.
-继续。-每次你停下来找吃的
-Go on. -Every time we stop for food,
-你就让我吃章鱼...-这味道很棒的！
-you make me eat octopus... -It's nice!
...或者是螃蟹眼睛、蜗牛的触须
...or crab's eyes or snail's legs.
每次当我们出发没多久，你就又要停下来
And then every time we get going again,you make us stop again
去看那些破砖烂瓦和童话故事里的阳台
to look at a pile of bricks and then that balcony from a story.
这是一次自驾游
It's a road trip.
我们就应该去游览一些...瞧瞧我带你去过的那些名胜
We're supposed to be seeing...Look what I've brought you to.
在路上
On the road.
我把你带到了我最喜欢的一家餐厅
I've brought you to one of my favourite restaurants.
-一张靠近海岸的餐桌...-这不是...
-A table for two by the waterside... -It's not...
快吃
Eat it.
-这不是一次美食之旅，是吗？ -快吃
-Not an eating trip, is it? -Eat it.
-吃掉章鱼肉。-它还在蠕动
-Eat the octopus. -It moved.
它没有。这只是它的一条腿而已
It didn't.It's only one of its legs.
我...
I...
你想找家高速路便利店
Would you like to stop at a service station
买包炸薯片吃吗？
and get some crisps?
午餐过后，我们来到海湾散步
After lunch, we went for a stroll along the seafront
顺便看看风景
to look at the sights.
但本片是一部定位家庭级别的娱乐节目
But because this is a family show,
所以某些画面我们必须要打上马赛克（阻碍人类进步的绊脚石啊~~~）
we can't show you what those sights were.
就这样，我俩欣赏着这片春色，直到手里冰淇凌融化殆尽
Eventually, though,our ice creams melted completely
之后我们又上路了
so we set off.
各位明白我们一直说的完美公路之旅是什么意思吗？
You know we were talking about the perfect road trip?
要是现在坐在兰博基尼和布加迪里那会显得多么不和谐？
How wrong would the Lamborghini and Bugatti have been here?
或者福特嘉年华
Or the Ford Fiesta.
-没错。-（笑）
-Yeah. -(BOTH LAUGHING)
克拉克森：问题在于当我们抵达圣拉斐尔时
CLARKSON: The problem is that when we arrived in Saint-Raphael
交通就如看见的这般糟糕
the traffic was predictable.
捷豹E型车也出毛病了
And so was the E-Type.
哈蒙德的爱驹发出了很不和谐的声音
Hammond's car is sounding poorly.
-（引擎异响） -噢，老天
-(ENGINE CLUNKING) -Oh, God.
它能在堵成这样的路况下坚持到圣特鲁佩斯吗？
Will it be able to do the traffic jam into Saint-Tropez?
呃...
Um...
说实话...我真的...
I'm honestly... I'm really...
我真为它担心，真的，我是真心的
I am worried about her,actually, I really am.
你确定？
Are you?
噢，老天，听上去不妙
Oh, God, that doesn't sound right.
克拉克森：来自60年代英国的特有声响
CLARKSON: The sound of Britain in the '60s.
嘀嗝-嘀嗝-嘀嗝-嘀嗝-嘀...
Ding-ding-ding-ding-ding...
（伯明翰口音）“诞生于英格兰中部的骄傲杰作”
(BRUMMIE ACCENT)"Made in the Midlands with pride.
“啊哈，我们把它装配的非常精良，确实如此，非常完美”
"Ah, we've really put this together very nicely, we have, very nice.
“那辆E型车是我们的杰作，我们的杰作”
"Done a good job with that E-Type, we have."
喔，油尺太烫了，完全不能碰
Ow, dipstick's too hot,can't touch that.
-噢。-理查德
-Oh. -Richard.
-什么事？ 我为你买了一件礼物
-What? -I've bought you something
让你振作起来
to cheer you up.
-你买了啥？ -这是件小礼物
-Have you? -It's a little present.
是吗？
Is it?
一个捞鱼网
It's a fishing net.
我知道这和你的E型车有些许不同
I know it's not the same as an E-Type
但你的车既然趴窝了，你就有机会用到它了
but now this doesn't work any more,you can have that.
谢谢你的鱼网
Thank you for my fishing net.
我花了三欧元，比你的车还贵（25元人民币）
It's three Euros,which is more than this is worth.
异口同声：目前如此
BOTH: Now.
克拉克森：之后我突发奇想
CLARKSON: I then had an idea.
我们现在开始一场比赛看看谁先到圣特鲁佩斯
We'll have a race from here to Saint-Tropez
但我们会在这留宿一晚，好吗？
but we'll stay the night, yes?
-比赛。-可我的车...
-A race. -What...
不
No.
-不用这些车。-弃用捷豹
-Ditch these. -Ditch the Jags.
你也没别的选择了
You've got no choice.
那家酒店叫什么名字？巴黎酒店
What's that new hotel called?Hotel de Paris.
-它有一个顶层酒吧。-是的
-It's got a rooftop bar. -Okay.
最后一个抵达那里的人
Last one there
必须穿上一件印有“我爱詹姆斯·梅”的T恤衫
has to wear an"I love James May" T-shirt
一整天
tomorrow, all day.
这是个比较狠的赌注，但是，呃...
That's quite a forfeit but, um...
我接受
Yeah.
哈蒙德：（拉链声）我想到一个绝妙的主意
HAMMOND: (ZIPPING UP) I have had such a brilliant idea
用来击败克拉克森
that Clarkson has had it.
因为我要用这个前往圣特鲁佩斯
Because I am going to Saint-Tropez on this.
杜卡迪Diavel
The Ducati Diavel.
黑暗系列
Dark.
-克拉克森：你准备好了吗，哈蒙德？ -准备好了
-CLARKSON: Are you ready, Hammond? -Yeah.
克拉克森：倒计时3，
CLARKSON: In three,
2，1...
two, one...
出发！
Go!
好的。
All right.
（叹气）
(SIGHS)
（奸笑）
(CHUCKLES)
我选择这辆摩托有着很好的理由
I chose this bike for a very good reason.
这车有一台1200CC V型双缸引擎
The engine,1200cc V-twin,
来自杜卡迪超级摩托1198
taken from a Ducati sports bike,the 1198.
对杜卡迪而言，相信我，在超级摩托制造领域绝对有两把刷子
And Ducati, trust me, know a thing or two about making fast bikes.
英国版本有162匹制动马力，
162 brake horsepower, the UK edition.
在法国由于受限制只有100马力
Restricted in France to 100.
但你知道吗？
But you know what?
这样的动力也足够我达成今天的目标了
That's still going to be plenty for what I want to do today.
最高时速170英里（273公里）
Top speed about 170,
0到60英里加速2.5秒（0-96公里）
0-60 about two and a half,
你懂的，这加速度和布加迪威龙一样快。（得意的笑）
you know, the same as a Bugatti Veyron.(LAUGHS)
堵车，瞧见了吧？
Traffic, you see?
在这种交通状况下他怎么可能比我先到？
How's he going to get to even this?
他甚至都不可能开出这个小镇
He's never even going to get out of town.
我看起来碉堡了。这车开起来就像阵风似的
I look cool. It goes like the clappers.
克拉克森一定被堵在其中
Clarkson's had it here.
走了。瞧见了吧？一路通畅！
There you go. See that? Clear!
哈罗
Hello.
欢迎光临Fairline Squadron 78型游艇
（Fairline：英国豪华游艇制造商）
You join me on a Fairline Squadron 78.
整艘船有78英尺长（24米）
That's 78 feet long.
这船的引擎规格让人难以置信
The engines in this thing are unbelievable,
排量32升，双涡轮增压V12引擎
32-litre, twin turbocharged V12s.
让我们乘风破浪吧
Here we go.
我甚至能像这样驾船
And you can drive it like this.
或者这样
Or like that.
同样因为它是艘船
And because it's a boat,
它能直接穿越海湾抵达圣特鲁佩斯
I could get to Saint-Tropez across the bay.
而哈蒙德却要绕着海湾前进
Whereas Hammond had to go all the way round it.
左摆右摆，穿过车龙，就是如此轻松
Sneaking through,sneaking through, just.
每辆车都有可能
Every car counts.
任何一辆车里面都可能藏着克拉克森
Any one of these could be Clarkson.
他在哪？
Where is he?
如果我路过他
If I have been past him,
他就会看见我穿着皮衣的背影，然后吃惊的喊道
he would have been looking at my bottom in leather, going,
“噢，看，那个穿着皮衣的男人”他会迷恋上哥的
"Oh, look, a man's bottom in leather."He's obsessed with it.
我不知道哈蒙德用的是交通工具
I don't know what Richard Hammond is using,
但我猜想
but I'm guessing
一定是摩托车之类的玩意
it's a motorcycle of some sort.
所以他一定全身裹着紧身皮衣
So he'll be dressed from head to foot in leather,
对着车龙大喊大叫
furious at the traffic,
屁股就像这样...（咆哮着）
with his bottom... (GROWLING)
“看看我，我骑着一辆超级摩托”
"Look at me, I'm on a motorbike.
“我驾驶着一辆疯狂的野兽！”
"I'm straddling a throbbing machine!"
我才不可能做出那么粗野的事
I'm not doing any of that.
卫星导航显示我们即将进入圣特鲁佩斯海港
Got the satnav down here to bring us onto the bearing of Saint-Tropez.
我只需要把转速稍微调高一点点
I'm just going to take it up a little bit more,
2300转
2300 rpm a side.
好好看看吧。学着点！
Look at this. Look at this now!
吃我的尾气吧，哈蒙德！
Eat my diesel, Hammond!
哈蒙德：我真希望在这些角落里
HAMMOND: I just want to come round one of these corners
看见一辆迈凯轮12C
and see a McLaren 12C.
或者一辆奔驰SLS黑色版本
Or an SLS Black.
他会被困在这里动弹不得。而我将从他的身边疾驶而过
And he will be stuck.And I will pass him.
我会问他“唔，摩托车
And I will ask him, "Mmm, bikes.
还觉得摩托车没用吗？”（大笑）
"Still no good?" (LAUGHS)
摄像组的同仁们有谁想来一杯的？
Anyone fancy a drink in the crew?
-都要？ -好的
-Yeah? -Yeah.
麻烦一下
Excuse me.
非常感谢
Thanks very much.
拥堵的车流。拥堵的车流
Standing traffic. Standing traffic.
出现吧，克拉克森，你在哪？
Come on, Clarkson, where are you?
当没人打开车门或左转时
As long as nobody opens their door or suddenly turns left,
我能一直在路中间这样行驶
I can just keep hacking through it like this.
噢，就怕这样。有人突然打开车门
Oh, there you go. That's the door open.
这只是其中之一而已
That's the one.
像突然开门的这种人不在少数
That's the fella. There's always one.
克拉克森可能就在这堆车里。我随时可能碰上他
He's going to be in any one of these.
Any minute now I'm going to see him.
这一定就是他了
This has got to be him.
女士们先生们，哈罗，杰瑞米·克拉克森
Ladies and gentlemen,hello, Jeremy Clarkson.
不，这不是他
No. That's not him.
克拉克森：在满船的欢歌笑语中
CLARKSON: With the Squadron at full chat
我们就要进入圣特鲁佩斯的海港了
and Saint-Tropez very close indeed,
船上的感觉真是太安逸了
life on the boat was good.
（嚎叫）瞎嘟囔
(GROWLS) Grunt!
我真是爱死这车了
This is more like it.
飞速驶近终点
Getting a proper move on.
摆脱了糟糕的圣特鲁佩斯大堵车
Having cleared the worst of the Saint-Raphael traffic,
我回到了正常路况极速前进
I was now on the open road and closing fast.
好吧，感觉起来，说实在的
Okay, there is, I'll be honest,
他只有很小的可能性
a tiny, tiny chance
穿过了密集的车流
he got through all of that traffic and out of town
抵达了这里的某个位置
and then caned it along here
到现在为止我还没发现他的踪影
and I simply haven't caught him yet.
但我还是怀疑
But I've got a good suspicion
当我们抵达圣特鲁佩斯时
when we get to Saint-Tropez,
还会有大堵车让我有机会逮住他
there'll be more traffic and that is where I'll find him.
我正准备把这艘78英尺长的游艇停泊进圣特鲁佩斯港
I'm about to park my 78-foot boat in Saint-Tropez harbour.
这是我目前唯一需要慢下来的事
This is the only slow bit,
圣特鲁佩斯港内必须减速
the wobbling about in Saint-Tropez harbour.
因为这里有愚蠢的限速规定
'Cause they've got some stupid speed limit.
（海鸥鸣叫）
(SEAGULLS SQUAWKING)
噢，亲娘，看这场面
Oh, good God, look at this.
-（喇叭） -交通状况。大塞车
-(HORNS HONKING) -Traffic. That's a big jam.
噢！
Oh!
蛇形前进，借过，借过
Squeezing through, coming through,coming through.
克拉克森：当哈蒙德
CLARKSON: As Hammond weaved his way
在圣特鲁佩斯车阵中龟移时
through the annual Saint-Tropez trafficjam...
噢，我的天
Oh, my God.
克拉克森：...我还在等海港调度员腾个船位出来
CLARKSON: ...I was still waiting to be given a parking space.
借过，借过，借过
Through, coming through, coming through.
（哈蒙德大笑）
(HAMMOND LAUGHS)
巴黎饭店，想死你了
Hotel de Paris, I thank you.
伙计！
Mate!
怎么样？
How are you?
哈蒙德：怎么可能...
HAMMOND: How...
老天，你看起来汗津津的
God, you look sticky.
这是搞什么鬼？
How the bloody hell?
我都没遇见过你。一次也没
I didn't see you.I didn't see you once.
我看见了一辆法拉利F12，我以为是你
I saw a Ferrari F12,I thought it was you.
事实是
Thing is
虽然你有摩托车驾照
you've got a motorcycle licence.
-没错。-但是，我却有
-Yes.-Well, now, I have
游艇驾照
a boat licence.
也就是说，显然，明天
And what this means, of course,is tomorrow,
你将要穿上一件非常拉风的T恤...
while you'll be wearing a T-shirt and that'll be cooler...
啊，我差点忘了还有这么件事
Ah, I forgot about that.
...T恤上会写着“我爱詹姆斯·梅”
...it will say "I love James May" on it.
（克拉克森坏笑）
(CLARKSON LAUGHING)
第二天早上，哈蒙德没显出一点着急
The next morning,Hammond was in no hurry
离开酒店的意思
to leave the hotel.
-哈蒙德。-干嘛？
-Hammond. -What?
-哈蒙德，出来吧。 -不
-Hammond, come out. -No.
不，我还要...我还没...我还在打包
No, I'm a bit...I haven't... I'm just packing my bag.
-已经8点45分了。-好啦，我只是在给我的行李打包
-It's quarter to 9:00. -Yeah, I'm just packing my bag.
我在打包
I'm packing.
事实上，不，我感觉不是很好
Actually, no, I'm not very well.
现在外面没人
There's nobody here.
-我感觉不舒服。 -哈蒙德！
-I'm poorly. -Hammond!
哈蒙德：好了。我出来了
HAMMOND: Right. I'm coming out.
唔。
Ooh.
现在，你看
Now, look.
-这真是太糟了。 -没错
-This is bad. -Yes.
但我恐怕还有比这更糟糕的事情
But I'm afraid the news gets even worse.
还有什么事能比我这件T恤更糟
It can't be any worse.
我们被要求驾驶同一款车
We've both chosen the same car.
好吧，但听上去还不算太糟，不是吗？
Well, that's not so bad, is it?
-你意思是只有一辆车？ -没错
-You mean there's only one? -Yes.
所以，圣特鲁佩斯
So, Saint-Tropez,
敞篷宾利，两个大老爷们
convertible Bentley, two men.
噢，我们看起来简直...
Oh, we are looking...
（不约而同地笑）
(BOTH LAUGHING)
才明白怎么回事
Just realised.
克拉克森：两个老爷们坐在同一辆宾利里
CLARKSON: Two men in a Bentley.
问题不在于我们开的是宾利，我们应该认识这点
It isn't just the Bentley,we ought to make that plain.
而在于这是辆敞篷车
It's any convertible.
把任何两个大男人塞进一辆敞篷车里
Put two men in a convertible car,
然后打开敞篷，问题马上就显现出来了
take the roof off and instantly, questions are raised.
哈蒙德：幸运的是在车里，外人看不见我的T恤
HAMMOND: Still, at least in the car,they couldn't see my T-shirt.
直到...
Until...
为啥要停在这？
Why are you pulling over here?
我突然想逛逛街
I just want to have a look at something.
-逛什么？ -一些东西
-What? -Just stuff.
-什么东西？ -只是...我想欣赏那些船
-What stuff? -Just... I want to look at the boats.
哈蒙德：你究竟想干什么？
HAMMOND: What are you doing?
-这地方很漂亮。-我不要停车
-It's a nice place. -I don't want to stop.
-这里到处是人... -下车吧
-There's people...-Just get out.
-哈蒙德：不。-下来
-HAMMOND: No. -Yes.
-哈蒙德：不！-下车
-HAMMOND: No! -Yes.
不，我要找个洞钻进去
No, I'm going to hide.
我绝不下车。就躲在这
I'm not getting out.I'm getting in here.
那我只好一个人了
I'm on my own.
哈蒙德：噢，天啊
HAMMOND: Oh, God.
我要去散散步，把他扔开一会
I'm just going to go for a walk and leave him.
哈蒙德：主啊，赶快结束这一切吧
HAMMOND: Make this end.
我打赌输了
I lost a bet.
哦，天啊
Oh, God.
杰瑞米，我们能离开这吗？
Jeremy, can we go now?
克拉克森：不
CLARKSON: No.
这些船哪些有螺旋桨
Do any of these boats have propellers
并且马上就要离开的？
and are any of them likely to be running right now?
又见狗仔队。这里有很多偷拍的人。
Paparazzi again.There's quite a lot of paps here.
没错。所以我们走好吗
Yeah. So let's go.
哈蒙德：但是，我们遇到了点小麻烦
HAMMOND: There was, however,a small problem.
克拉克森：这里...哈蒙德：我们的车原来是停在这吗？
CLARKSON: Was it... HAMMOND: Is this where it was?
-是啊。-好吧，现在没了，怎么回事？
-Yes. -Well, it's not, is it?
我猜可能是这么回事
I tell you why it's not.
这里是禁止停车的，你觉得呢？
You can't park here, can you?
这里允许停车吗？你能在这...什么？
Can you park here? Are you allowed to... What?
好吧，显然这里是禁止停车的，而我们的车被警察拖走了
No, you can't park here or that's a picture of a car being towed.
-你知道吗，我实在是...-车是被拖走了对吧？
-Do you know, I genuinely... -Has the car been towed away?
好吧，看上去的确如此
Well, yes.
你在这等一会
Just you wait here
我把车要回来
and I'll go get it.
-放轻松。 -是啊
-Just relax. -Yeah.
离得不远，真的，一个小时就回
It's not far, actually,I'll be back in an hour.
我确定曾经某人也一定和我一样不爽
I'm sure somebody somewhere at some time has been unhappier.
别这样，别这样，别这样，别这样
Please, please, please, please.
别这么干，这一点也不好玩。
No, not funny. Not even halfway funny.
打开这该死的门。杰瑞米，开门
Open the damn door.Jeremy, open the door.
你怎么能这样？
How do you do that?
我上车了
I'm getting in.
克拉克森：现在，你们一定在疑惑
CLARKSON: Now, at this point you may be wondering
为什么我们被要求同乘一辆宾利
why both of us chose a Bentley.
好吧，事实其中一部分原因是它很漂亮
Well, partly it's because we think that these days, it looks good.
但主要原因是它性能出色
But mostly it's because it's now available
搭载了一台优秀，轻质，高亢的4升V8引擎
with a brilliant, lighter,louder 4-litre V8.
但这些优点在哈蒙德思维里都不是最重要的
Not that this was foremost in Hammond's mind.
-杰瑞米·克拉克森。-什么
-Jeremy Clarkson. -Yes.
你把我的座椅加热给打开了吧？
Have you put my seat heater on full?
是的，没错。
Yes, I have.
噢，伙计，这简直是...
Oh, mate, that's...
-是的，这就是真相。-噢！
-Yes! Result. -Oh!
太难受了。
Just horrific.
-这就是症结所在。-噢！
-That's a result right there. -Oh!
克拉克森：接着我发现了另一个原因
CLARKSON: Then I got another result.
一条干净，通畅的道路
A clear, open road.
（伯明翰口音）“稳住你的脊椎”
(BRUMMIE ACCENT)"It's got a bit of poke."
-哇噢！-噢，这才是它应该发出的声浪
-Whoa! -Oh, that's how it should sound.
克拉克森：你认为这车感觉上去像什么？
CLARKSON: Do you know what it feels like?
-一台跑车。-没错
-An sportscar. -It does.
你把我的座椅加热给打开了吧？
Have you put my seat heater on?
是的，没错
Yes, I have.
（大笑）我真是太...
(LAUGHING) I'm really sor...
这是一台速度机器
It's a machine, this.
你好，极品飞车！
Hello, machine!
其中一个我喜欢这车的原因是
One of the reasons why I like this car so much,
你知道这车不只是贴了宾利的标志那么简单而已
you know it isn't just a Bentley badge,
这车使用了最复杂的汽车工程技术
there's some properly difficult engineering that's gone into this car.
杰瑞米，你又把我的座椅加热给打开了吧？你这个...
Jeremy, have you put my seat heater on again? You...
-（笑）-这真不...我...
-(LAUGHING) -That's not... I...
噢
Oh.
如果我坐起来，外面的人就会看见我的T恤
And if I lift myself up,they can see my T-shirt better
如果我坐下，我就热死了。天啊！
and if I sit down, I cook. God!
克拉克森：所以，很棒的引擎
CLARKSON: So, clever engine,
优秀的四轮驱动系统
clever four-wheel-drive system,
这些真不错
looks a lot better these days.
哈蒙德：迷人的声浪
HAMMOND: Great noise.
克拉克森：没错
CLARKSON: Great noise.
真是一辆好车
't's a great car.
问题在于这车还是给人一种鲁尼的感觉
The problem it has still is that Rooney flavour.
鲁尼的感觉就是说
The whiff of Wayne means
当别人看见你驾驶着这车会让你觉得很尴尬
you do feel embarrassed to turn up in it.
哈蒙德！
Hammond!
不要再打开我的座椅加热
Stop putting my seat heater on.
很快，抛开座椅加热，火辣的宾利，以及炙热阳光的问题
Soon, despite the hot seats,the hot car and the hot sun,
车内的气氛变得十分低沉
the atmosphere became frosty.
所以我们决定再次分开
So we decided to split up.
接着我决定去看看附近一座历史悠久的古建筑
And then I decided to look at a building that had mostly fallen over.
看这个
Look at this.
看啊，这是一头野猪，这里
Yes, look, there's a wild boar,there we are.
这是一幅狩猎图
This is a hunting scene.
哈蒙德，这是一幅狩猎图！
Hammond, there's a hunting scene!
哈蒙德！
Hammond!
感觉这里原来是座陵墓
It's like there's a mausoleum
-或者是个凯旋门之类的建筑。-不要和我讲这些，我不关心
-and a sort of triumphal arch. -Don't talk to me, I don't care.
我不想听这些。我不想知道，我不想听！
I don't want to hear about it.I don't want to know, I really don't!
这些让我恶心
I'm sick of it.
这太荒谬了。我出来这一趟吃过了螃蟹眼睛
This is ridiculous.I've eaten crab's eyes,
看过了故事里的阳台。说真的，这回该轮到我做主了
I've looked at a balcony from a story.No, seriously, it's my turn.
这回我要决定我们接下来做什么
It's my turn to decide what we do next.
我们接下来要跑一场拉力赛
And what we're doing next is going rally driving.
-什么，就用玛莎拉蒂总裁？-不
-What, in a Maserati Quattroporte? -No.
-和一辆劳斯莱斯幻影？-不
-And a Rolls-Royce Phantom? -No.
我有个好主意
I've had a good idea.
哈蒙德：这是桑布尔赛道
HAMMOND: This is the circuit Sambre,
永无止境且严酷无比的一条法国拉力赛道
endless kilometres of unrelenting French rally stage.
这个地方Stig很熟悉
And a place The Stig knows well.
-什么？-是这么回事
-What? -Well,
这里是Stig的避暑山庄，懂吗？
this is The Stig's summer retreat, yeah?
他每年都来这里跑圈
He comes here every year and does that.
-他说过...-你说跑圈是什么意思，跑什么圈？
-And he says... -What do you mean, he does that?
是这样，冬天他去跑雪地比赛。夏天他来这
Well, in winter he goes ice racing.Summer, he comes here.
连跑三周的拉力练习圈
Three weeks of that he does.
-什么，一刻不停？-没错，坐进车，连续不断跑三个星期
-What, non-stop? -Yeah, gets in the car, three weeks,
三个星期之后，下车，回家
and then three weeks later,gets out, goes home.
这是他的度假方式。先不说这个，他同意我们借用
That's his holiday.Anyway, he says we could use it
这条赛道跑几圈拉力赛
to do our rally driving.
-现在太热了。-哈！
-It's too hot. -Dah!
我已经考虑到了这一点
I have actually thought of that.
-你喜欢敞篷车，是吗？-是的
-You like a convertible, don't you? -Yeah.
那为什么我们不用敞篷车来跑一场拉力赛呢？
Why don't we rally-drive convertibles?
-那会很脏。-现在，请跟着我做一件事
-It's too dusty. -Now, do one thing for me,
我们去找些敞篷车
we're going to go and get some convertibles,
然后把它们改装成拉力赛车跑拉力赛！
turn them into rally cars and do that!
我不会跑拉力赛
I can't do rally driving.
-这很简单，只要...-我不行！
-It's easy, just... -I can't!
我不能在野地里开车...
I can't drive on loose surfaces...
这就是我的座驾
This is what I've got.
日产350Z
Nissan 350Z.
3.5升V6引擎
Three-and-a-half-litre V6,
276制动马力，后驱
276 brake horsepower, rear-wheel drive.
现在，你看着这车，可能在想“好吧
Now, you might be looking at it, thinking, "Well,
这车看上去不怎么像拉力赛车”
"it doesn't look much like a rally car."
但先别急着下定论，这车有一个血亲
But hold on,this car is a direct descendant
日产Datsun 240Z
of the Datsun 240Z,
一款曾经横扫世界拉力锦标赛的名车
a car that owned world rallying.
所以它有拉力血统
So this has got history.
它会表现很出色
It's going to be brilliant.
我找到一辆宝马
I've got a BMW.
没有拉力血统，我选它因为我喜欢这车
No history of rallying at all,it's one of the reasons I like it.
好吧，说说看，给观众介绍介绍这车的引擎？
Well, come on, tell us about it,what engine has it got?
2.5升直列6缸
Two-and-a-half-litre straight 6.
哈蒙德：排量比日产低了1000cc。动力呢？
HAMMOND: 1000cc less than the Nissan. Power?
我猜大概192？
192?
那也比我的车少了80马力。扭矩多大？
That's about 80 horsepower less.Torque?
180牛米
180.
-同样低了80。-很好！
-That's about 80 torques less. -Good!
-你说很好啥意思？-很好！
-What do you mean, "good"? -Good!
杰瑞米，你没有表现出真正的竞赛精神
Jeremy, you're not really getting into the competitive spirit of this.
我不喜欢在没有附着力的地面上开车！
I don't like driving without friction!
哈蒙德：敞篷拉力赛将会是下一个兴起的运动大项
HAMMOND: Open-top rally is going to be the next big thing.
让我们开始改装我们的战车吧
Let's go and convert these into rally cars.
接下来是激情改装加配乐时间
This meant finding a workshop and cueing the music.
（过场音乐）
(THEA-TEAMTHEME PLAYING)
克拉克森：搞定
CLARKSON: Got it.
噢，很好
Oh, yes.
老天，我真天才
God, I'm good.
这会让我的战车小宇宙爆发
That will make up for the horsepower deficit
哈蒙德的车上也有这个
that I have on Richard's car.
我是八月车神
This is August.
请叫我四月骑士
Now Mr April.
我的防滚架完工
My roll-cage is complete.
哈蒙德：第二天，我们的车都已蓄势待发
HAMMOND: The next day,our cars were ready.
-老天爷也很给面子。-（电闪雷鸣）
-And so was the sky. -(THUNDER CRACKING)
万事俱备，只欠东风
This is alljust fantastic.
突然间，完美的拉力天气也即将降临
Suddenly, perfect rallying weather is coming.
一点点雨水，泥土，山间的薄雾
Bit of rain, mud, mist on the hills,
我的车已经准备就绪
and my car is now perfect.
并没有爆改
Haven't gone over the top with the modifications.
只是换了新轮毂，新轮胎，加装了防滚架
New wheels, new tyres, roll-cage,
赞助商贴纸，不能用真的
sponsorship stickers,can't have real ones,
这是BBC的规定，但我们尽可能营造真实气氛
BBC objects, but we've made 'em up to put you in the mood.
内部，拉力座椅，多点式安全带，足够了
Inside, racing seat,full harness, that's enough.
这会是一次另人惊叹的比赛
This is going to be amazing.
我就是学着他的样子依葫芦画瓢而已
I just copied him.
现在他准备开着他的日产在泥地里撒欢了
And now he's going to drive about in his Datsun in the mud.
哈蒙德：他说的没错，我已经迫不及待了
HAMMOND: He was right, I couldn't wait.
噢，真爽！
Oh, yes!
真的下雨了，我在跑拉力赛。太完美了！
It's actually raining, I'm in a rally.This is perfect!
（哈蒙德大笑）
(HAMMOND LAUGHING)
在尝了那么多愚蠢的食物，看了那么多破砖烂瓦后
After all the stupid food and looking at rocks,
我终于干了一件让我兴奋异常的事...
to come out and do something genuinely exciting and real and...
我又充满了激情
I've come alive.
哦，太棒了！
Oh, yes!
（雷声大作）
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
哈蒙德正在这样的大雨里在外面抽风
Hammond is out now in that.
他简直疯了！
The man is insane!
来吧，再下大点。来啊！
Bring it on, let's have more. Come on!
这也叫下雨？
You call that rain?
（大笑）
(LAUGHING)
（大笑）喔！
(LAUGHING) Oh!
现在这里是这个世界上我最喜欢的地方
This is my favourite place in the world now.
（雷雨交加）
(THUNDER CRACKING)
哈蒙德：啊哈！
HAMMOND: Ah!
抱歉，哈蒙德，给我解释解释
I'm sorry, Hammond,do try to explain it to me,
我实在难以理解
'cause I'm struggling to get it.
这是本次旅程中我干过最爽的事情了
It's about the most fun I've had in a very long time.
我能理解为什么Stig经常来这了
I can see why The Stig comes here.
-你全身是泥。-是的
-You're covered in mud. -Yeah.
-外面雷雨交加。-是的，我知道
-There's a massive thunderstorm raging. -Yeah, I know.
我明白，没有比这更好的天气了。太完美了
I know, even the weather's better here.It's perfect.
你说更好是什么意思？
What do you mean, it's better?
（雷声）
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
（开门声）
(CAR BEEPING)
-哈蒙德，我一定要这么干吗？-是的
-Hammond, do I have to do this? -Yep.
（叹气）今天我做主，这就是我们今天的任务
(SIGHS) It's my thing today,and this is what we're doing.
克拉克森：就这样，为了表现出我是个多么大度的人
CLARKSON: Andso, to show what a good sport I am,
我逼着自己出发了
I obliged.
噢，上帝啊！
Oh, God's truth!
噢！真疼
Oh! That hurt.
真难受...
So, discomfort...
噢！真是太恶心了！
Oh! That's just horrible!
危险
Danger.
悲惨，湿冷
Misery, cold.
打滑让我只能开到21英里的时速（34公里）
Slithering around at 21 miles an hour.
哦，不！见鬼...
Oh, no! Bloody...
我洗了个泥水澡
I've just had a brown shower.
原本以为这一圈就结束了
That really was the final straw.
（雷声）
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
后来才发现噩梦远没结束
And then it turned out it wasn't.
好的，刚才是热身圈，我们已经熟悉了赛道，对吧？
So, we got the hang of it,we now know the course, yeah?
现在开始跑计时赛
Time for timed laps.
-什么？-是的，现在开始跑计时赛
-What? -Well, we do timed laps now,
这才是正题。我觉得我们每人再跑上十圈
that's what we do.I reckon if we do 1 0 each
就能得出谁是最优秀的车手
and then we can just work out how consistent we are,
在成绩上一见高低，怎么样？
where we can just shave those extra seconds out, yeah?
明天，我会请你吃
Tomorrow, you are going to eat
野熊的蛋蛋
a badger's left teste.
克拉克森：结果，我们全然不顾外面的瓢泼大雨
CLARKSON: Andso, flying in the face of common sense,
又回到了赛道上
we got back out there.
计时赛，所以这回是动真格的
Timed laps now, so it's really critical
要勇敢地踩下油门
to just be brave enough to keep that power in.
（哈蒙德大笑）
(HAMMOND LAUGHING)
克拉克森：计时赛有什么意义？
CLARKSON: What's the point of timed laps?
他比我多80马力...噢！...比我多得多
He's got 80 more horsepower...Oh! ...more than I have.
他比我更擅长玩这个
He's better at it than I am.
他配置了限滑差速器
And he's got a limited-slip differential.
我什么都没有
I haven't got one of those.
所以每当我过弯，我的一个轮子就会打滑
So, when I go round the corner,one wheel spins and that's it.
哦嚯！天啊，当你做出完美滑行的时候那感觉太爽了
Woo-hoo! God, it feels good when you get it right.
哇噢！
Whoa!
噢!哦，我的天！
Oh! Oh, my!
（大笑）
(LAUGHING)
他也会...
He will have been...
噢，看见他了，我能从这里看见他的大白牙
Oh, here he comes,I can see his teeth from here.
好的，拉力赛的弯道超车。真有意思
Right, overtaking on a rally stage.This is interesting.
克拉克森：噢，他超过了我！
CLARKSON: Oh, he's coming through!
噢，不！丑陋的伯明翰小矮子超过了我！
Oh, no! The hideous little Brummie has torn past!
啊哈！追上你了！
A-ha! Got you!
噢，他居然这么干...噢，他全都做到了
Oh, he's done it...Oh, he's just made everything
更糟的是，我看不见任何东西
much worse now, I can't see a thing.
一片模糊
Muddy goggles.
（呻吟）
(GROANS)
我真想把他弄成残废
Every bone in his crotch,that is what I'm going to break.
（大笑）
(LAUGHING)
喔！
Oh!
克拉克森：很快，天气变得越来越糟
CLARKSON: Soon, the weather got so bad,
甚至哈蒙德也看不清赛道了
even Hammond couldn't see where he was going.
见鬼！见鬼！噢！
Shit! Shit! Oh!
克拉克森：因此，他提议先暂停，享用一顿拉力午餐
CLARKSON: So, he suggested we stop for one of his special rallying lunches.
唔。尽情享用
Mmm. Okay, tuck in.
-真的？-唔-唔
-Really? -Mmm-hmm.
这是法国本地的特色热狗
'Cause this part of France is famous for its hotdogs.
这上面抹了法式芥末酱
It's got French mustard on it.
-是的...-等等
-Yeah... -Wait a minute.
什么？
What?
你知道这热狗肠里都是些什么吗？
You do know what's in that sausage, don't you?
-香肠。-猪蹄子
-Sausage. -Pigs' toenails,
猪的睫毛...
eyelashes...
闭嘴快吃。趁你享用美食的时候，我手里已经有咱俩的成绩了
Shut up and enjoy it. And, anyway, while you enjoy it,
I've got the timings here.
我在1分16秒，13秒之间
I'm around the 1:16, 1:13,that kind of mark.
-唔-唔。-你的成绩在1分53，46...
-Mmm-hmm. -You're 1:53,1:46...
克拉克森：泥巴都进到我的耳朵里了！
CLARKSON: I've got soil in my ears!
1分35，1分40...基本上，可以看出
1：35,1：40... Basically, what this is showing is that I am clearly
我比你快得多
a lot better at this than you.
-我要和你再打个赌。-什么？
-I'll do you a deal. -What?
我们再跑一圈。
We will do one more lap.
生死战
Do-or-die lap.
如果我赢了，我立马消失
If I'm faster, we leave immediately.
-如果你比我快？-是的
-If you're faster than me? -Yes.
好吧，但如果我更快，我们就玩到天黑
All right, well, if I'm faster,we carry on till dark.
-你能做到？-唔-嗯
-You'll do that? -Mmm-hmm.
-认真的？-嗯-嗯
-Seriously? -Mmm-hmm.
好吧
All right.
哈蒙德：我第一个出发
HAMMOND: I went first.
（法语）
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
我们出发了
And we're off.
好的，现在，我不止要击败他，我还想羞辱他
Right, now, I don't want to just beat him, I want to humiliate him.
噢，是的！这才对
Oh, yes! That was correct.
噢！
Oh!
驶过一个大坑
That was a monstrous dump from below there.
上帝也加入了这场角逐
Nature is joining in with us now.
噢，这真是太有趣了
Oh, this is just epically good fun.
（碰）
(THUDS)
完事，杰瑞米，我觉得你如果比我慢上一分钟
All right, Jeremy, I reckon if you get within a minute of that,
我都会错愕不已。你没机会的
I'll be staggered. Not a chance.
克拉克森：我胸有成竹地
CLARKSON: Filled with determination,
把车停在了起跑线
I lined up the BMW on the start line.
（法语）
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
好的，我要赢下这场比赛
Right, I am going to win this
这样我们就能结束这无聊的一切
and then we can stop doing it.
这里...哦！等等
That's... Oh! Hang on a minute.
很好！
Yes!
你觉得怎么样？
What do you think of that?
悄悄的。是的！
Sneaky beaky. Yes!
（克拉克森奸笑）
(CLARKSON LAUGHING)
是的！
Yes!
上帝是站在我这边的
The gods are on my side.
这将是伟大的一圈！
This is going to be one hell of a lap!
我们汇合对比成绩
We then met up to see how we'd done.
理查德·哈蒙德，你成绩是1分17秒3
Richard Hammond, you did it in one minute,17.3.
-虽然不是我最快的成绩但也不错。-很好，这是个标杆
-Not my fastest but not bad. -Well, it was a standing start.
是的，确实，当然是的。没错，继续，你的呢
It was, yes, of course it was.Yes, go on, then.
-我的成绩，28秒...-然后？
-Me, 28 seconds... -Yes?
一分多少？
One minute what?
就是28秒
28 seconds.
你的一分在哪里...
How did you find a minute in the...
-我想说...-因为我是车神
-I mean... -Ultimate driving machine.
以及优秀的宝马Z4
And a BMW Z4.
是嘛？
Really?
克拉克森：我立刻走人
CLARKSON: I left immediately.
开始完成去到波城的最后350英里（563公里）
And set off on the 350-mile drive to Pau
驾驶着一辆阿斯顿马丁V12
in a V12 Aston Martin.
哈蒙德，则开着一辆大众甲壳虫（新911）
Hammond, meanwhile,was in a Volkswagen Beetle
而气氛，依旧阴沉
and moaning, as usual.
他作弊的手段越来越下流
His cheating is getting out of control.
这一切都因为他用Stig作弊和超近道变得毫无意义
There's no point doing anything if he's just going to borrow The Stig
这是他这些天做的所有下三滥事情
or cut a corner, which I can only imagine is what he did in that instance.
他一定只跑了一个弯道，连作弊都做得这么没技术含量！
It must have been one hell of a corner, he can't even cheat well!
我承认我超的近道确实短了那么一点点
I admit my shortcut was a bit short.
而且圈速确实离谱了那么一丢丢。但是你瞧
And the time was a bit implausible.But look,
天气变好了而且我现在开上了阿斯顿马丁征服
the weather is improving and now I'm in an Aston Martin Vanquish.
这是一辆高贵华丽的车
This is a truly magnificent car.
至今为止最棒的阿斯顿
Best Aston yet, by a long way.
它柔和了DBS的刚猛
It's a blend of the hardcore DBS
也借鉴了Virage的舒适
and the slightly softer Virage.
这真是极好的
It's just tremendous.
现在我要把镜头交给哈蒙德
And now I shall hand you over to Richard Hammond,
他会向各位解释为什么他开的911
who shall try to explain why the Porsche 911
在某些方面和前N代的版本
that he's driving is in some way different
有所不同
to all the Porsche 911s that have gone before.
（转速声）
(REVVING)
他怎么能说911都是一个样？
How can he go on about 911s all being the same?
让我给大家揭揭阿斯顿马丁系列的老底
Let me talk you through the Aston Martin range.
Vantage V8, V12 Vantage
Vantage V8, V12 Vantage,
DB9, DBS, Virage,以及前面那货
DB9, DBS, Virage, that,
它们事实上都是一回事
they're all exactly the same.
阿斯顿马丁设计出了一款车
Aston Martin came up with the design,
觉得，“噢，这车看起来真漂亮”
thought, "Oh, that looks pretty.
“让我们给它起N个名字这样就会有更多人买它了”
"Let's call it lots of different things and then more people will buy it."
他开的车就是这么个玩意
It's just another one.
C2, C2S, C4, C4S
C2, C2S, C4, C4S,
GT2, GT3, Turbo, 997, 996, 993...
新一代911被称作911
The new 911 is called the 991 ,
它比前作更长更宽
it's longer and wider than the previous 911 .
搭载了新款发动机，新型变速箱，新的内饰，以及新的转向系统
It's got a new engine, new gear box,new interior and new steering.
这是个有争议的点，有史以来
This is the critical point,for the first time,
保时捷第一次用电子转向系统取代了纯液力转向机构
the steering is electric rather than purely hydraulic.
正当我兴致勃勃的讲解时
Just as I was getting into the groove,
杰瑞米又把车开下了高速路
Jeremy pulled off again.
又要干啥？
What now?
这样，既然明天就要抵达波城了，我认为
Well, I thought it would be a good idea,since we're at Pau tomorrow,
我们应该体验一回高附着力赛道
to reacquaint ourselves with the concept
的驾驶概念
of driving while under the influence of friction.
我不喜欢摩擦力
I don't like friction.
波城，伙计。那可是波城
Pau, mate. It's Pau.
那里从1901年就开始举办比赛了
They've been racing there since 1901 .
范吉奥曾经驰骋在那
Fangio has raced there,
吉姆·克拉克，杰基·斯图尔特。那是座名城
Jim Clark, Jackie Stewart.This is a big deal.
那里是...对车迷而言那里就和伯利恒在基督世界的地位一样神圣
（伯利恒：巴勒斯坦中部城镇，相传耶稣和大卫的诞生地）
This is... It's Bethlehem for any motoring enthusiast.
那这和我们要去的地方有什么关系？
So, what's it got to do with that?
我们要先在这里热热身
We've got to get match fit.
然后明天当我们真正去到波城时...
And then when we get to Pau tomorrow...
-我们就会不虚此行。-嗯-嗯
-We'll be worthy of it. -Mmm-hmm.
（引擎声）
(ENGINES REVVING)
克拉克森：在大直道上，我热血喷张
CLARKSON: Straightaway,I was very happy.
赛道没水，也没泥土
No wet track, no mud,
没有下雨，也没有白喉（白喉：一种急性呼吸道传染病）
no rain, no diphtheria.
这是一条又窄又曲折的短小赛道
This is one tight and twisty little track.
好的，现在，让我们把这辆阿斯顿
Right, now, let's turn the Aston
从公路车变成赛道怪兽
from a road car into something more track-based.
我要按下这个按钮，这会提升悬挂的支撑力
We'll push this button here,that firms up the suspension,
接着按下这个按钮，S，我想这是代表“愚蠢”的意思
and then push this one,S,I think it stands for "silly".
因为你按下它之后...准备好了吗？
'Cause when you push it... Ready?
整辆车都变了“嗯，什么？”这就像是对一条宠物狗发出命令“走！”
The whole car goes, "Hmm, what?"It's like saying "walkies" to a dog.
“噢，你确定？走你？”
"Oh, really? Walkies?"
（引擎声）
(REVVING)
这车的引擎和经典的阿斯顿马丁征服上那款一模一样
This has the same basic engine that was fitted to the original Vanquish.
而那款车的竞争对手是法拉利550
And that was comparable at the time to the Ferrari 550
和575
or 575.
从那以后，法拉利前进了许多，如今他们拥有了F12
Since then, Ferrari have moved on,they're at the F12 now.
（轮胎啸叫）
(TYRES SCREECHING)
这货甚至连双离合变速器都没有
This doesn't even have a double-clutch gearbox.
还是一台老旧的七速序列式变速器
It's an old 7-speed slushmatic.
每档切换都像一位老管家慢慢地为你送至面前
Each gear is delivered by an elderly butler.
“我想要三档，贾维斯”“好的，先生，我马上
"I'd like third now, Jeeves.""Certainly, sir, I'lljust
为您送上三档。我想它一定被收藏在我的橱柜里，
"pop off and get it.I think it's in my pantry.
三档来了，先生。”
"There you are, sir."
虽然在公路上很平顺，但在赛道上却不是那么回事
Very smooth,lovely on the road, not brilliant here.
这车感觉像一艘方舟
It's a bit of an ark, this.
华而不实
It's a very pretty ark.
但当你把它摆进一个弯道时...
But when you stick it into a corner on a track...
你能感受到在这碳纤维车身的外表下
you know that beneath the carbon fibre body,
一切都似曾相识
everything's a bit old.
倒不是说旧就不好，正如你所看到的一样
Not that there's much wrong with old, as you can see.
与此同时，在距我千里之外的某处...
Meanwhile, far behind...
哈蒙德在他的911里体验着生死时速
Hammond was revelling in the new 911 's grip.
天呐，这抓地力太惊人了
God, this thing is planted.
依旧是熟悉的3.8升水平对置6缸引擎
Still a 3.8-litre flat six,
依旧被安装在车尾，依旧短小紧凑
it's still mounted at the back of the car, it's still compact.
最大的不同，就是它的这套电子转向系统
The big issue, though,is that electric steering.
感觉它没在和我交流。它没有...它应该通过前轮的轻微滑动
It's not talking to me. It's not...It should be telling me everything
来为我提供详尽的路感
by going slightly light at the front under power.
也就是说前轮相比较其它的普通汽车
It means the front wheels can move around a little bit more
应该再提升些许的自由度
than they would in an ordinary car.
并且方向盘的回馈感应该告诉我这些信息
And the steering wheel should be telling me about that,
所有这一切会让我知道这是一辆911
that's what lets me know it is a 911
而不是一辆R8或者一辆捷豹
and not an R8 or a Jaguar.
这车感觉像911吗？
Does it feel like a 911?
我不这么认为
I don't think it does.
到了波城，我希望有一辆比911更出色的车型
And for Pau, I want something that's more of a 911.
我也想到了自己到底想要的是什么
And I've had a very good idea for that.
我应该选这辆车
I shall be using this,
全新的保时捷911 GT3
the brand-new Porsche 991 GT3.
我非常渴望驾驶它
I am desperate to drive it.
因为它质量更轻，底盘更低，速度更疯狂
It's lighter, lower, faster.
它就是我的独角兽
This is my unicorn,
我的女神
my Helena.
克拉克森：GT3或许在这里很强大
CLARKSON: Track-focused the GT3 may be,
但到了波城，它连我座驾的尾气都吃不到
but at Pau, it would be no match for my choice.
单座BAC Mono跑车
The single-seater BAC Mono.
Top Gear赛道有史以来最快纪录车型
One of the fastest cars ever to take on the Top Gear test track.
纯粹简约，极度轻量化，异常敏捷，一流的平衡性
Purity simplified,light, agile, balanced.
简称完美
Perfect.
就当工作人员为我们重要日子的用车做检查之时...
As men set about fettling our cars for the big day...
我们又重温了一遍本次旅行用到的各种
we ruminated on all the boats and bikes and cars
游艇，摩托车，跑车
that we'd used on ourjourney.
-哈蒙德！-（笑）
-Hammond! -(LAUGHING)
我们也试图找出一款最优秀的交通工具
And we tried to work out which one we'd liked the best.
（尖叫）
(SCREAMING)
我喜欢那辆福特嘉年华ST，我真的很喜欢
I loved that little Fiesta ST,I really did.
我喜欢驾驶那辆福特T型车，虽然它开起来很疯狂
I actually loved driving the Model-T,crazy though that is.
我喜欢那辆杜卡迪
I enjoyed the Ducati.
但出于某些原因，法拉利F12给我留下了很深的印象
But for some reason, the Ferrari F12 has really stayed with me.
我认为它既高贵又漂亮而且还很快！
I thought it had presence and drama and it's fast!
我不会选SLS因为它体积太大，不适合日常使用
I wouldn't have the SLS 'cause that's too much to use every day.
高尔夫GTI又太小了
Golf GTI isn't quite enough.
布加迪威龙，我是说它又是另一个级别的产物了
Bugatti Veyron, I mean it's the other end of the scale, then.
高出太多。宾利...
Too much. Bentley...
噢，是辆不错的车但是...我想出来了我喜欢什么
Oh, it's a great car but...I've worked out what I'd have.
丽娃Aquarama（那艘豪华游艇- -#）
The Riva Aquarama. (LAUGHING)
-那是你最喜欢的车？-是的
-That's your favourite car? -Yes.
如果我天天用它，我估计得搬家
That's what I'd use every day.I'd have to move house.
得出结论之后，我们爬进各自的爱车
With that decided,we climbed back into our road cars
前往最后的目的地波城
for the final push to Pau.
我们对前方的圣城是如此兴奋
We were very excited by what lay ahead,
以至于我们不顾摄制组的后勤车一骑绝尘
so excited that we left the camera crew far behind.
当他们再次赶上我们的时候，我们遇到了一点小麻烦
And when they finally caught up with us,there was a bit of a problem.
（警察无线电通讯，模糊不清）
(POLICE RADIO CHATTER, INDISTINCT)
克拉克森：你是说，护照？
CLARKSON: You mean, passports?
噢，好吧
Oh, right.
那边的法国男警官和女警官
The French policemen and lady policemen
坚持让我们交出随身携带的所有的现金（难道遇上劫道的了...）
insisted that we should give them all our money.
最后经过漫长的交涉
And then after quite a long chat,
他们决定如果我们不在法国驾车就允许我们入境
they decided it would be best if we didn't drive in France any more.
好吧，就这样
Yeah, okay.
随着这则爆炸性消息，又到了节目结束的时候
And on that bombshell,it is time to end.
非常感谢各位的观看，再见
Thank you very much for watching,goodbye.
你这个白痴！
You total plonker!
我不想搭标致或者波罗
I don't want to go in a Peugeot or a Polo.
或是这辆沃克斯豪尔赛飞利
Or this Vauxhall Zafira.
搭顺风车的人能这么挑剔吗？
Can you be picky when you're a hitchhiker?
我觉得可以。这有太多车可以选择了
I should think so.There's plenty of choice.
不想上那辆雪铁龙
Don't want to go in that Citroen.
遗忘天下，个人翻译，如有错误，万望海涵
译制：遗忘天下 后期校订：遗忘天下 上传：遗忘天下
QQ号：529098103 欢迎车迷同学加好友
（最后20秒有惊喜）